<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Early-infighting</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/early-infighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/early-infighting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GraniRau/status/1622394754666201089&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An often overlooked fact is that Greek and Roman rule saved many Jews from being persecuted  by other Jews. The Maccabean dynastic period was one round of persecutions and forced conversions by Jews on Jews after another. The Romans got involved there because of Jewish infighting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;King Jannaeus had Pharisees crucified by the hundreds because he supported a different type of Judaism.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Samaritans were persecuted by other Jews and had their temple destroyed.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Idumaeans were forced to become Jews at sword point.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There was a temple in Egypt founded by Jews and a branch of the priestly dynasty who were run out of the Jerusalem temple, yet more infighting over religion. The high priest claimant Onias was assassinated by other Jews near or at the Grove of Daphne while under Greek protection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Judeo demographics in Rome</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/judeo-christian-demographics_in_rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/judeo-christian-demographics_in_rome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That Xtians &amp;amp; Jews had higher growth rates isn&amp;rsquo;t much in doubt, classical authors mention it. Tacitus is explicit on Jewish growth being due to their pro natalism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How much growth over 300 yrs can never be determined now, just guesswork &amp;amp; obv Xtians have an incentive to overplay their numbers to make it out like Rome becoming Xtian was some inevitability, so I take Stark&amp;rsquo;s estimates with a pinch of salt. You can&amp;rsquo;t just indefinitely project 7 kids per women because as the groups bigger it gets harder &amp;amp; harder to swim against constraints that begin to impose themselves, just like how Iranian mullahs encouraged a baby boom during war with Iraq but then implemented family planning when they realized they couldn&amp;rsquo;t provide jobs for the youth bulge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local-context-removal</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/local-context-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/local-context-removal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1478009608992083972.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A cult is NOT the God itself. An idol is not the God, mythology is not the God. But they do connect people to the God. A cult arises when a God is worshiped in a particular context, place, time, way, purpose. Santa Muerte is death, something undeniably real.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting more into this topic, as it is one of the major things that distinguishes paganism from Judaism. Judaism started as a project to do away with all this context. This was to do away with and prevent the founding of new cults. It didn&amp;rsquo;t start as monotheism but one temple ism. Monolatry doesn&amp;rsquo;t filly describe it either, as it isn&amp;rsquo;t just the worship of one God, but in one place, in one way, with one priesthood. This was very unusual, the only thing prior that even approached this was Akhenaten, he may have had this in mind for his new capital city. It effectively locked the vast majority of people from even worshiping yahweh most of the time. And even if they went to Jerusalem to do so they mainly served the role of buying a sacrificial animal and handing it to the priests. Who often sold the animals in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orthodoxy spectrum</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/orthodoxy-spectrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/orthodoxy-spectrum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is from conversations online.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ultra-orthodox-orthodox-liberals&#34;&gt;Ultra orthodox, orthodox, liberals&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ultra-orthodox&#34;&gt;Ultra-orthodox&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ultra-orthodox are a faction apart, and many of them are non-expansive in either a philosophical or marital sense. Their view of the tradition is purely as a training routine, and propagation as purely biological. Their psychological drive comes from a set of inward-looking concepts that I will come to later.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;haredi-and-zionism&#34;&gt;Haredi and Zionism&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Haredi view Zionism as blasphemous sacrilege that is trying to establish a Jewish state without the sanction of Yahweh. Haredi believe the Jews have been cursed by Yahweh to be a stateless people until the  Messiah comes. Think of them as Shrautin Agnihotris of Jews.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real case agaisnt jews</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/real-case-agaisnt-jews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/real-case-agaisnt-jews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://patriot.dk/ravage.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Real Case Against Jews&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following is an article written by an American Jew in 1928&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Marcus Eli Ravage&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reprinted from The Century Magazine January 1928&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, you do resent us. It is no good telling me you don&amp;rsquo;t. So let us not waste any time on denials and alibis. You know you do, and I know it, and we understand each other. To be sure, some of your best friends are Jews, and all that. I have heard that before once or twice, I think. And I know too, that you do not include me personally - &amp;ldquo;me&amp;rdquo; being any particular individual Jew - when you fling out at us in your wholesale fashion, because I am, well, so different, don&amp;rsquo;t you know, almost as good as one of yourselves. That little exemption does not, somehow, move me to gratitude; but never mind that now. It is the aggressive, climbing, pushing, materialistic sort you dislike - those, in a world, who remind you so much of your own up-and-coming brethren. We understand each other perfectly. I don&amp;rsquo;t hold it against you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tacitus on Jews</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/tacitus_on_jews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/yahUdonmAdaH/articles/tacitus_on_jews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Meta&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before he starts to describe the Roman siege of Jerusalem, Roman historian Tacitus offers an account of Jewish history. The translation of Histories 5.2-5 was made by Kenneth Wellesley.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Jews are said to have been refugees from the island of Crete who settled in the remotest corner of Libya in the days when, according to the story, Saturn was driven from his throne by the aggression of Jupiter.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
