<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Breeding on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/breeding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Breeding on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/breeding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>67k_isis_females</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/breeding/67k_isis_females/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/breeding/67k_isis_females/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Important thread : Why opposition to an anti-ISIS movie? B&amp;rsquo;coz many do not want common Indians to remember how a brutal, bloodthirsty, slave owning, genocidal terror organisation enjoys wide support in men and women globally. Just look at these samples&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When ISIS was defeated, many of the women who went there were already dead. Some died fighting, some became suicide bombers, some were killed in airstrikes and some killed brutally by ISIS fighters for refusing to provide sex or trying to escape. Still 67000+ women and children remained. Yes, 67000! They came from all over the world. Atleast 81 countries. Most of them were perfectly happy with Kafirs slaughtered &amp;amp; raped as per Islamist beliefs. Most have not showed remorse even for the sake of returning to their countries. Don&amp;rsquo;t be fooled 1/4&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inbreeding Iran</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/breeding/inbreeding_iran/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/breeding/inbreeding_iran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/QuaziShehnaaz/status/1195934914346131456&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iran appears to have the world&amp;rsquo;s highest rate of lifetime infertility because it also has the world&amp;rsquo;s highest rate of STD infections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iran, like other Middle Eastern countries, has an extremely high infertility rate. More than 20 percent of Iranian couples cannot conceive, according to a study conducted by one of the country&amp;rsquo;s leading fertility clinics, compared with the global rate of between 8 and 12 percent. Experts believe this is due to the prevalence of consanguineous marriages, or those between cousins. Male infertility is &amp;ldquo;the hidden story of the Middle East,&amp;rdquo; says Marcia Inhorn, a Yale University medical anthropologist and a specialist on assisted reproduction in the region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>isis stud-farm</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/breeding/isis_stud-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/breeding/isis_stud-farm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opindia.com/2023/02/isis-women-force-boys-teenage-islamic-population/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ISIS women force boys as young as 13 to impregnate them to increase Islamic population, gave them Viagra-like substance&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a horrific incident, teenage boys at Camp al-Hawl in northeast Syria were forced to have intercourse with dozens of ISIS women held in Syrian detention camps. The women forced young boys to forcefully impregnate them to enhance the Islamic population.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The incident came to the fore when two young boys named Ahmet, 13, and Hamid, 14, approached the guards at the camp and said, “We are being forced to have sex with the ISIS women, to impregnate them. Can you get us out of here?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK Grooming</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/breeding/uk-grooming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/breeding/uk-grooming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opindia.com/2020/07/muslim-grooming-gangs-uk-victim-narrate-details-rape/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Muslims have raped at least 5 lakh Kaffirs in the UK in last 40 years,” says survivor of Pakistani grooming gangs- Read excruciating details&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shedding pretentious nuances surrounding discussions related to race and religion, Dr. Elisa Hill emphasised, &amp;ldquo;A lot of it has to do with race and religion. A lot of people don&amp;rsquo;t like talking about it or they don&amp;rsquo;t like to hear about it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;26 July, 2020&lt;br&gt;&#xA;OpIndia Staff&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
