<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Anti-hindu patterns on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Anti-hindu_patterns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Anti-hindu patterns on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Anti-hindu_patterns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hindu to sikh</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Anti-hindu_patterns/hindu-to-sikh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Anti-hindu_patterns/hindu-to-sikh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/arya_amsha/status/1632099057358475264&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1891, there were a total of 4.4 million Jats in Punjab Province (Haryana plus Hill States included). Hindu Jats were the most numerous at 1.7 million, followed by Muslim Jats at 1.6 million and Sikh Jats at 1.1 million.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, a rapid shift was to happen as in just a few decades there was a mass shift of Jats away from Hinduism to Sikhism combined with higher Muslim fertility rates and in the 1931 census, Hindu Jats had become less numerous than their Sikh and Muslim counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iconoclasm</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Anti-hindu_patterns/iconoclasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Anti-hindu_patterns/iconoclasm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;naina-devi-incident&#34;&gt;naina devI incident&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The story makes clear that the Guru didn&amp;rsquo;t approve of this case of vandalism over-interpreted as iconoclasm. The mockery of the goddess&amp;rsquo;s idol can be applied to any religious object, e.g. the Guru Granth. Set it on fire &amp;amp; it won&amp;rsquo;t defend itself, nor will it rat on you. Lifeless.&amp;rdquo; - KE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In short, after the battle of Kartarpur he went to Phagwāra. From there, since it was difficult for him to stay in any place near Lahore, he proceeded to Karaitpur (Kiratpur) which is situated within the Punjāb hills. That area belonged to Rāja Tärächand, who did not pursue the path of allegiance and obedience to King Shāhjahān. The people of that area worshipped images. On the top of the mountain an image of a goddess, known as Naina Devi has been set up. Rājas and others from the territories around, going to that place, followed the custom of making a pilgrimage [to it]. When the Guru settled himself there, a Sikh of his, Bhairū by name, going to the temple, broke the nose of the goddess. The Rājas got the news of it and complained to the Guru, taking his [Bhairu&amp;rsquo;s] name. The Gurū summoned Bhairū. Bhairu denied it. The Rājas&amp;rsquo; servants said, “We recongnise this (man).&amp;quot; He replied, &amp;ldquo;O Rājas, ask the goddess. If she takes my name, you can kill me.&amp;rdquo; The Rājas said, &amp;ldquo;Fool, how can the goddess speak?&amp;rdquo; Bhairū broke into laughter, saying, “One now knows who is the fool. When she cannot prohibit anyone from breaking her own head, and cannot identify the person who has attacked her, what good do you expect from her, and why do you worship her?” The Rājas were put to silence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>khAlistAn context</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Anti-hindu_patterns/khAlistAn_context/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Anti-hindu_patterns/khAlistAn_context/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hinduism is a minority religion in Punjab. During the Khalistan movement, the minority Hindus and Jains were subjected to several attacks. Hindu and Jain temples were frequently vandalized and desecrated. This thread documents a few instances.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is to be noted that many of these incidents happened prior to the Operation Blue Star carried out by Congress Government in 1984. The attacks of Hindu temples were not confined to just Punjab. The radicals crossed over Punjab into Haryana and bombed Hindu temples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
