<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Subversion as a constituent on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Subversion as a constituent on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Economic damage to society</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/01_Economic_damage_to_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/01_Economic_damage_to_society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Indian economic share went down due to the trauma of Islamic invasion. [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2012/06/the-economic-history-of-the-last-2-000-years-in-1-little-graph/258676/&#34;&gt;At16&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/1ntHuop.png&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/1ntHuop.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/1ntHuop.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;economic-punishment&#34;&gt;Economic punishment&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About a certain Islamic ruler of India: &amp;ldquo;Muslims were exempted from paying the housetax and taxes on grain and other goods meant for their personal use. Hindus converting to Islam were exempted from specific taxes. Special attention was given to the education of Muslim children. Towards the end of his reign Muslims made up a very large majority of his senior most nobility.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Or consider historian Prof. KS Lal’s works on caste and religion, refuting with primary data the seeming truism, launched by the Communist Party ideologue MN Roy and now omnipresent in the textbooks, that the lowest castes converted en masse to Islam because of its claimed message of equality. Islam mainly won over the urban middle castes (and not because of equality, a value rejected as ingratitude towards the Dispenser of destinies in the Quran, but because of the privileges vis-à-vis non-Muslims), not the Untouchables. Again, the silent treatment has been the only response the “experts” could muster.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pragyata.com/mag/academic-bullies-278&#34;&gt;KE16&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;parasitic-relation-to-the-other&#34;&gt;Parasitic relation to the other&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A summary from @parikramah:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Criminal activity</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/02_Criminal_activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/02_Criminal_activity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The findings: about 80% of the criminals at the petty-crime level were Muslims, that figure decreasing when it came to white-collar crime. Please note that under the Indian Penal Code, petty crime includes armed robbery, dacoity and attempted murder - all of which carry heinous penalties by Shariat, which was the point in discussion.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rediff.com/news/sep/05varsha.htm&#34;&gt;RED&lt;/a&gt; 2005 varShA]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kerala-records&#34;&gt;Kerala records&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Via divodAsa:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apart from recorded history, the local folklore of Kerala also narrates about Moplah troublemakers. The local legends recorded in Aithihyamala, a popular collection of legends by Kottarathil Shankunni also narrates how the Muslims were troublemakers in the kingdom of Cochin [10]. It narrates the story of Kochi king Rama Varma Shaktan Thampuran on how he executed a Moplah who slaughtered a cow in the kingdom. Another story from same work narrates how Shaktan Thampuran executed a Moplah who tried to sexually assault a Nambuthiri Brahmin lady while her husband was away [11] and also talks about punishment given by Shaktan Thampuran to Moplah thieves who pillaged the travellers [12].&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Inhibiting religious practice</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/04_Inhibiting_religious_practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/04_Inhibiting_religious_practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;chaitanya-mangala, vijaya gupta&amp;rsquo;s poem on Husain Shah summarized &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/Nktg3CY.png&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.voiceofdharma.org/books/siii/ch10.htm&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; - Caveat: Goel &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?tbm=bks&amp;amp;q=The+wicked+mlechhas+pollute+the+religion+of+the+Hindus+every+day&amp;amp;cad=h&#34;&gt;misattributes vijaya-gupta-quote&lt;/a&gt; to gangAdEvI).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Temple and university destruction</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/05_Temple_and_university_destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/05_Temple_and_university_destruction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This can happen as government policy or as a matter of riots.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Summary: Muhammad&amp;rsquo;s example as *the ideal muslim* has motivated murderers and pillagers throughout the ages, including in my country. Like early christians who burnt down the library of Alexandria, they destroyed the great universities of naLandA and vikramashIlA, the temples they razed are too numerous to count - zarathruShTa&amp;rsquo;s favorite tree, the sphynxes nose, tombs of Timbuktu, buddha-s of bAmiyAn being well known examples in the wider world.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;iconoclasm&#34;&gt;Iconoclasm&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;limited-digestion-of-polytheism-and-icon-worship&#34;&gt;Limited digestion of polytheism and icon worship&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sufi and shia dargah-s provide for some limited outlet for polytheistic and iconophilic tendencies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Other cultural degradation</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/06_Other_cultural_degradation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/06_Other_cultural_degradation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;cruelty-to-culturally-important-animals&#34;&gt;Cruelty to culturally important animals&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Torturing dogs in zoroastrian areas of Iran [&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/stream/APersianStrongholdOfZoroastrianism/BoyceMaryaPersianStrongholdOfZoroastrianism#page/n79/mode/2up&#34;&gt;arch&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cow killing in India.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;‘Ala Hazrat’ the founder of Barelvis, arguably one of the top “reformers” of the Indian Mohammedans of the last century, wrote a Fatwa tract in early 1900s entitled Qurban-ul-Bakr, that made it mandatory for Indian Moslems to slaughter Cow instead of other animals. He said a particular thing becomes mandatory for M in reaction to any initiative that dilutes the full limits of Sharia. Therefore, he argued, since some want M to give up cow slaughter and use other animals since Sharia allows it, while it is normally fine, but because it “limits” the practice to reduced allowance of full Sharia, it becomes mandatory for Muslims to react by slaughtering cows only. Normally it would have been permissible but in reaction, it is mandatory.&amp;rdquo;  {&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Gxw6okCPURA?t=678&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;}&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>halAl</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/halAl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/constituent-subversion/halAl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;geopolitical-push&#34;&gt;Geopolitical push&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A cartel of Islamic countries (led by pAkistAn and malaysia) insist on all imports (even non-meat food and non-food products like cement) having a halAl certificate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;GoI FSSAI Green dot certifying absence of meat not respected by them - they insist on halAl certificate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;consequence&#34;&gt;Consequence&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The most intolerant minority wins&amp;rdquo; rule of NN Taleb applies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;halAl slaughter requires muslim butcher. So, companies are forced to hire muslims and exclude non-muslims.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For efficiency reasons, in the absence of sufficient pressure from non-muslims, it does not make sense for companies to hire two sets of workers for the same product.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the absence of strong non-muslim reaction, non-halAl meat is then not even available to customers who prefer that. For example, airlines prefer to stock and provide only halAl meat (caterer SkyChef supplies halAl meat only).&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Halal meat is cheaper, and most customers never bother complaining. Theoretically, halAl should be more expensive (peculiar requirement of a minority community). Amazing how the tables are turned due to the &amp;ldquo;intolerant minority&amp;rdquo; principle.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To access 0.25x of the market, non-muslim companies are forced to go for halAl certificate - even when it makes no sense to do so (eg. non-meat products, Ayurvedic medicine). So, they are forced to pay local muslims for nothing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reaction&#34;&gt;Reaction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Insistence of reciprocity&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If muslims refuse to eat meat butchered by Hindus (&amp;ldquo;won&amp;rsquo;t be halAl&amp;rdquo;), why should Hindus eat meat butchered by Muslims? (Many non-muslims - including hindus and sikhs since many hundred years - insist on jhaTka meat.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If muslims insist on part of the profits going to other muslims for useless certification (even on non-meat and non-food items) - should hindus not reciprocate in kind?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If GoI FSSAI Green dot certifying absence of meat is not respected by Islamic countries, why should non-muslim countries respect food certification of Islamic countries?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Government protection of non-muslim work-force and consumer choice&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Insist that stores, trains and airlines carry jhaTka meat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interesting but over-long video on the halAl tax - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CNNnews18/status/1509859167363899393&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/CNNnews18/status/1509859167363899393&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
