<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Raudgrani on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/raudgarni/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Raudgrani on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/raudgarni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amalekite assacre</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/raudgarni/amalekite-assacre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/raudgarni/amalekite-assacre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GraniRau/status/1977899374823841833&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Remember what Amalek did to you on the way as you were coming out of Egypt,  how he met you on the way and attacked your rear ranks, all the stragglers at your rear, when you were tired and weary; and he did not fear God.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You forgot the 400 year time gap. Saul&amp;rsquo;s massacre of the Amalekites was 400 years after the events described. David also has a later massacre of the Amalekites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biblical marriage sex</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/raudgarni/biblical_marriage-sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/raudgarni/biblical_marriage-sex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1289362681758023680.html#google_vignette&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;motive&#34;&gt;Motive&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We all see things on Greece and Rome all the time. The pop history version(from Christians and Hollywood) would have you think that non-Jewish/Christian society was a big free-love clusterfuck. I am tired of seeing this ignorance. So to shine a light on the issue, I figured why not go over the Biblical and historical Christian mores, just a bit. Many people mistake modern Western mores for being &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Christian&amp;rdquo;. This is not the case.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Damned infants</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/raudgarni/damned-infants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/raudgarni/damned-infants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Augustine believed that all unbaptised infants were damned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;St. Gregory, the pope, also spelled out this doctrine. And it was official doctrine for most of history. Capeshit is a good term for it. I don&amp;rsquo;t think most Christians believe the religious stuff is real. If I literally believed my God puts infants in hell I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be &amp;hellip;worried about some ancient cultures practicing infanticide or modern day abortions. The god is a million times worse than any human could be. But most don&amp;rsquo;t believe in this doctrine even where it is on the books or logically applies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Euro traitors</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/raudgarni/euro-traitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/raudgarni/euro-traitors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/LogosGermanorum/status/1977085439480619092&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have total Christian exhaustion. They are, for the most part, traitors, anti-Europeans who rejoice in the destruction of our pagan heritage in the name of the god of the Jews. They have no intellectual honesty, they are in a seemingly permanent state of cognitive dissonance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter what you tell them, no matter how many rabbi clips you show them, they will insist that Jesus was not a Jew. I don’t believe many of them are capable of any level of critical thinking, they hate the Jews, yet they can’t even tell you why, because their hatred is confined to the insane belief that they “killed God”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human sacrifice</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/raudgarni/human-sacrifice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/raudgarni/human-sacrifice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human Sacrifice as a Biblical Practice&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many will tell you that the Israelites did not practice human sacrifice to Yahweh. The evidence is to the contrary. There is a bias toward this claim because our view of that ancient people is colored by the biases of Abrahamic claims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a topic I had intended address from the start. Human sacrifice is in the Bible, particularly the Old Testament or Tanakh. Some cases are well known, but it is actually much more common than most know. Language and translation conceal an important concept.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
