<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Esther Dhanraj on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Esther Dhanraj on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Catholicism - Luther protection</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/catholicism_luther-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/catholicism_luther-protection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1523641874279325698.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Catholic Church tortured &amp;amp; killed those that simply rejected their teachings; burnt at stake those that questioned them - But somehow spared Martin Luther - the guy who led a whole protest against Catholicism, nearly uprooting their dominion. Ever wondered why?  Read on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By 16th c. the Church became very powerful &amp;amp; dominant. Thereby corrupt. It had immense political &amp;amp; spiritual power over the Roman empire and the emperor. It made salvation a business enterprise. It began selling INDULGENCES saying ppl&amp;rsquo;s punishment for sins could be reduced. What are INDULGENCES? Catholic Christianity of that time taught that sin was of 2 types: Mortal sin which directly earned hell after death &amp;amp; Venal sin which was a few years of purification in purgatory - an interim state between life on earth &amp;amp; eternal life in heaven. It was promoted widely that purchasing Indulgences could reduce time in the purgatory. Priests, aristocrats, entrepreneurs who wanted money for their projects would hire salesmen (pardoners/quaestors) to sell indulgences. Corrupt salesmen soon started promising salvation itself. The quaestors forced ppl to buy indulgences from them. They threatened eternal damnation to those who refused to buy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>God as author of evil</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/God_author_of_evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/God_author_of_evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1529062744753786881.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christians that claim that their god YHWH is not author of evil must go back to the basics of their religion. In the early stages of Jewish theology YHWH &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;the satan&amp;rdquo; were used interchangeably. As their theology evolved Satan became a proper noun &amp;amp; a separate being from YHWH. Compare an early writing: 2 Sam.24.1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Again the anger of YHWH burned against Israel &amp;amp; HE incited David against them, saying, “Go &amp;amp; take a census of&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Historical jesus</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/historical-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/historical-jesus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.rattibha.com/thread/1786976293629608043&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;What every Hindu must say to a Christian that comes to &amp;ldquo;share the gospel:&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;first get a clarity on whether Jesus even existed &amp;amp; if he did, what exaclty he taught &amp;amp; then come to preach.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is a brief insight into how shaky the grounds are on which Christianity stands today.&#xA;Thomas Jefferson: primary author of the Declaration of Independence called the original sin, virgin birth &amp;amp;resurrection as superstitions &amp;amp; fabrications; calls NT writers ignorant, unlettered men; creates his own bible, strips J of divinity; reduces him to just another philosopher&#xA;Who said America was founded on Christian values?? &amp;amp; Jefferson was not alone. Many thologians have rewritten accounts of Jesus&amp;rsquo; life to compensate for deficiencies in the NT.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus birth dating</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/jesus-birth-dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/jesus-birth-dating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1546475391925174273.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hilarious to still come across videos from self-styled apologists in India repeating the outdated, now debunked lie which goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dionysius Exiguus, the 6th century monk dated the birth of Jesus to Dec 25th based on the year of the founding of the Roman empire.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The date for the founding of the Roman empire itself is shrouded in mystery. Imagine how accurate the dating for Jesus is. Modern #ChristianMythologists fraudulently promoted that every historical event is dated based on the birth of Jesus. This is the greatest lie ever told.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus name</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/jesus-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/jesus-name/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1435209294547324934&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1435209294547324934&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People&amp;rsquo;s names, regardless of language and culture usually carry a meaning. What does Jesus mean in any language? Nothing! Don&amp;rsquo;t believe me? Read on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jesus and his followers were all Jewish and so they had Hebrew names, although they would likely have spoken Aramaic. “J” soundw in Jesus’ name does not exist in Hebrew or Aramaic. So, the actual name is “Yehoshua”, pronounced, Yeh-ho-shoo-ah. This name is the blending of two Hebrew words:Yeh-ho + Shua. Yeh-ho = Jewish god’s name, sometimes used at the beginning or end of a Hebrew name. Shua = Hebrew word for deliverance, meaning, SAVES. Yehoshua literally means JEWISH GOD SAVES. The name Yehoshua was then cut short the same way Rajesh becomes Raju; Srinivas - Srinu; Rajeshwari - Rajjo/Raji. Thus, the 4-syllabled name Yehoshua became the 3-syllabled Yeshua.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>King James bible origins</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/king-james-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/king-james-bible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1443143836776030211&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1443143836776030211&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Heard of King James version of the Bible? Know of its origins in this thread.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 382 CE, Jerome was commissioned to translate the old and archaic Latin versions of the bibles into everyday Latin. This was the Vulgate. Even then only the educated elite &amp;amp; priests could read it. They acted like mediators between believers and the Christian god, reading and interpreting it for the common people. Now we know how and why so many interpretations arose out of each verse. This gave them scope to corruption within the church. This went on till the 1500s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kolkata teresa</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/kolkata-teresa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/kolkata-teresa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/kamakshidhanraj/status/1841958261970419872&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On October 7th, the Missionaries of Charity will complete 74 years. This proselytization factory was founded by the Vatican agent from Albania, Gonxha Agnes Bojaxhiu (GAB) who later became Teresa of Calcutta.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot has been said about her cruel Vatican agenda carried out in India. Her love for attending photo opportunities, award ceremonies and social gatherings with the world&amp;rsquo;s oligarchy, callous and greedy predators, corrupt and fanatical cult leaders is all in the public domain now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protestants &amp; Tanakh</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/protestants_tanakh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/protestants_tanakh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why do Protestants disown the Tanakh (Old Testament) claiming, the only part that they have anything to do with it is the so-called prophecy of Jesus mentioned in Isaiah 7:14? That is because even they find most of the contents absurd, indecent, sexual, graphic, so on. Talking snake &amp;amp; donkey told as historical events, their god&amp;rsquo;s mandate to kill babies, his act of drowning innocent animals, his curse to dash infants to the ground, rip open pregnant wombs are too absurd &amp;amp; violent to the modern minds. And so the best thing to do is disown it. But as masters at cherry picking, they pick the so-called prophesy because it justifies Christianity&amp;rsquo;s dominion theology. It is the Christian political ideology of establishing a Christian world nation in the name of saving the world from damnation through the grace of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Witch hunt in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/witch-hunt-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/esther/witch-hunt-scotland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1450320753195319298&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1450320753195319298&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-side-of-king-james-of-bible-fame&#34;&gt;Other side of King James of Bible fame&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Witch-hunting is an extension of the Protestant Reformation! 1000s of respected, elderly, even godly women were tortured in the most gruesome manner PURELY on suspicion of them possessing magical powers. It all emanated from the disturbed childhood of one psycho- King James.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The psycho has two names: King James VI of Scotland &amp;amp; King James I of England. The third title he has is The Witch-Hunter Psycho King. Christian historians only highlight him for creating the King James Version &amp;amp; have deliberately hidden his monstrous, phobic, maniacal side.+++(5)+++ In his James VI, king of Scotland avatar, he commissioned the witch trials &amp;amp; executions. As the Hindi saying goes,“सौ चूहे खाके बिल्ली चली हज को,&amp;quot; in his James I, king of England avatar, he commissioned the King James Bible translation. The KJV must be named MJV. M= Monster. Christianity preaches: people that take up godly tasks like Bible translations can do it only by the lead of the holy spirit.+++(5)+++ So, James was apparently led by the holy spirit for commissioning the Bible. What spirit was he led by for hunting witches? Evil? Holy &amp;amp; evil at the same time?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
