<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Abrahamisms on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Abrahamisms on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Counter-religions</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/counter-religions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/counter-religions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;definition-in-opposition&#34;&gt;Definition in opposition&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A counter religion is defined in &lt;em&gt;opposition&lt;/em&gt; to another, pre-existing natural religion (though they may falsely claim to be the &amp;ldquo;original&amp;rdquo;). This opposition is a core part of a counter religion, and not incidental.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, we have the first two of the 10 commandments, combined with universalism - &amp;ldquo;You shall have no other gods before Me. You shall not make for yourself a carved image.&amp;rdquo;; implying the existance of &amp;ldquo;False Gods&amp;rdquo;. Similarly, in a later evolute we have - &amp;ldquo;Mohammed is the last prophet, and he supersedes all predecessors&amp;rdquo;. Hence, such religions are said to be &lt;em&gt;defined&lt;/em&gt; in opposition to others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hindu response</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/hindu-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/hindu-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Military response - see &lt;a href=&#34;../../../polity/external-affairs/defence/&#34;&gt;defence page&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2014/02/04/some-notes-on-the-extra-military-aspects-of-the-islamo-hindu-confrontation/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt; posits: &amp;ldquo;Mohammedanism needed special backing for its effective survival in the subcontinent. &amp;hellip; Demographic and missionary aggression by Mohammedanism might not have been sufficient for it to overrun the Hindu dharma.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For generic intellectual and identity based response patterns, see &lt;a href=&#34;../../../polity/external-affairs/defence/id/&#34;&gt;defence/id page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The striving for non-Hinduness might have even lead to internal rifts within Mohammedanism as each group was trying be more Mohammedan than the other. &amp;quot; [&lt;a href=&#34;http://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2014/02/04/some-notes-on-the-extra-military-aspects-of-the-islamo-hindu-confrontation/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-the-nature-of-abrahamist-god&#34;&gt;On the nature of Abrahamist God&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A classical vaidika hindu view would be:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The Gods are and always were in perfect harmony. Myths of their battles, though sacred and valuable, are not to be taken literally. So this monopolistic God is at best petty human misinterpretation, and his cults are deadly memetic epidemics.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With rare exceptions, all abrahamisms agree on some basic concepts. Abrahamisms have certain indispensable beliefs (dogmas), without which the thought-system would collapse. (Aksharananda &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WN0JQsgZJas&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.) Particular exceptions case of &lt;a href=&#34;../0-theism/&#34;&gt;0-theism&lt;/a&gt; is considered separately.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;fundamental-incompatibility-with-paganisms&#34;&gt;Fundamental incompatibility with paganisms&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The principles of Abrahamism have been fundamentally formulated as &amp;ldquo;non-heathenism&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1064698752517226496&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;true-vs-false-gods&#34;&gt;True vs False Gods&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;true God and false gods (supposedly unwitting followers of Satan), universal urge for religion/ divinity, religion (= worshiping the true God, rejecting false gods)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;References&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;BG &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MDNTP53TCxA&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MDNTP53TCxA&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hegel&amp;rsquo;s excellent observation &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/TLjScks.jpg&#34;&gt;IMG&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marxists.org/reference/archive/hegel/works/pc/tubingen.htm&#34;&gt;prospects_folk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;pagan-criticisms&#34;&gt;Pagan criticisms&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;God&amp;rdquo; of the Abrahamists is not even real - it is but a psychotic demonic memetic construct, a part of a widespread mental disease. Abe&amp;rsquo;s monotheists are actually mentally ill atheists, for whom the Abrahamist God is a coping mechanism to compensate for the dissatisfactoriness of their atheism. Or, they may be viewed as mentally ill polytheists, who have (in their heads) turned ALL Gods into demons - including their - now psychotic - &amp;ldquo;One True God&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problem समस्या</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;zero-sum-game&#34;&gt;Zero sum game&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;National anthem, Cashmereyaut, suppression of dummy grad students etc are mere facades for the really elephant in the room that H themselves are afraid to see &amp;ndash; there can be no coexistence between Abe and the heathens &amp;amp; Abe will do all it takes to make us fertilizer for the soil.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/762346994333519873&#34;&gt;TW16&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-natural-polytheisms-why-the-big-deal&#34;&gt;Why natural polytheisms? Why the big deal?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;objections&#34;&gt;Objections&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let everyone get along by just belonging to the same religion - all roads lead to God. Why the confusion?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;polytheism can continue with angels and saints under monotheism (as in folk catholicism) - so no need to resist and fuss about its preservation&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;objective-answers&#34;&gt;Objective Answers&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Monotheisms are a serious memetic disease of epidemic proportions which naturally sap the genius and vitality of individuals and communities. So, it is best to fight and minimize this disease as much as possible.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Better connection to the universe, better care for our environment, more creativity (via greater freedom and superior access to truly divine inspiration), less energy spent on proselytization that uproots people from their ancestral cults &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Intolerance for intolerance is essential - anything else is suicidal. More in &lt;a href=&#34;../../../polity/external-affairs/tolerance/&#34;&gt;tolerance page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;You live in a world of multiplicity. Multiplicity is inherent in just you alone, a single being; with multiple limbs, organs, sensory faculties, etc. Multiplicity in colours, tastes, smells, etc. Why won’t there be a multiplicity on the divine? Polytheism recognises this ubiquitousness of multiplicity &amp;amp; offers you a way to access this divine multiplicity in this very mundane world through these very mundane things. Suddenly, the 8 directions of the compass, colours, shapes, etc have something transcendental to offer. Monotheism only offers you a gloomy, empty &amp;amp; sinful world and a permanently displeased singularity of “God”, outside whom there is no choice to access the divine as per one’s proclivities and nature. You have to be a very insipid/dry human being to be a monotheist.&amp;rdquo; - GA. (Another response in the same vein - &lt;a href=&#34;https://agnimaan.wordpress.com/2019/03/30/if-there-is-a-god-there-is-only-one-fallacy/&#34;&gt;KV19&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also see: particular &lt;a href=&#34;../../../hinduism/benefits/&#34;&gt;benefits of hinduism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;fat-tail-risk-analysis&#34;&gt;Fat tail risk analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;namby pamby polytheisms - get gobbled up by monotheist contagion. Examples:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;most polytheisms - especially those of senescent pagan civilizations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;monotheisms (eg. Islam) - make anti-science nuts, overconstrain creativity, bloody &amp;ldquo;real monotheist&amp;rdquo; squabbles, spur dark ages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;virile polytheisms: ~0. Examples:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;japanese shinto + buddhists who expelled Portuguese and stamped out Christianity&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;subjective&#34;&gt;Subjective&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Having to hide and secretly preserve one&amp;rsquo;s polytheistic beliefs from dormant or active monotheist enforcers is irksome for polytheists.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our Gods are real and desire and deserve devotion without being hidden inside an oppressive faith&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Further, it is in a sense &amp;ldquo;claustrophobic&amp;rdquo; and ugly for polytheist devotees.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As a certain pUjA put it: &amp;ldquo;Sauron has reached out far and stretched his nazgul arms wide indeed. What will the hobbits do now? Gandalf? Aragorn? The elves? The hobbits are all drinking to their health in the Green Dragon while the shire, no - Middle earth, is threatened. Dark days are indeed at our doors. I hope the Frodo in us is kicked up back alive by the ever loyal Samwise.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Worship Restrictions</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/worship-restrictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/worship-restrictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Abrahamic Worship&amp;rdquo; vs &amp;ldquo;pUjA&amp;rdquo; (=adoration) distinction. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t9-bFtSKie0&amp;amp;index=7&amp;amp;list=PL6DF39CE9DE9554AD&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X4b3hfoUUNQ&amp;amp;list=PL6DF39CE9DE9554AD&amp;amp;index=12&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=67KEqTYNXr8&amp;amp;index=13&amp;amp;list=PL6DF39CE9DE9554AD&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pl0seNsxMTs&amp;amp;index=14&amp;amp;list=PL6DF39CE9DE9554AD&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Abrahamic concept of worship is more rigid - God tells you how he should be served in revelations; you cannot go worship him through idols, for example. So there  is the concept of &amp;ldquo;right worship&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;false worship&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By contrast, pUjA can take many forms. Consider: आकाशात् पतितं तोयं यथा गच्छति सागरम्। सर्वदेवनमस्काराः केशवं प्रति गच्छति॥&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The famous Abrahamist objection to  goes: &amp;ldquo;Worship the creator, not the creation.&amp;rdquo; Implying that one is forced to have a dichotomy between the creator and his creation in matters of worship.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The target of pUjA need not be Gods or deities. Does Ayudha-pUja necessarily imply in the mind of the worshipper that a Maruti Car is a God? Is such a belief even required? Even if one considers the car to be one of the places where the divine resides, this still contrasts with the notion of Abrahamic worship which would prohibit such &amp;ldquo;idolatory&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Belief in a certain dogma is important in worship, but not in pUjA. Christian belief is that worship of false Gods takes you to hell.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;pUjA is more flexible: doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any fixed belief - it may only require the concept of sahRdayatA while performing the pUjA; the fact that it has to do with emotional well being rather than physical well being; that the beliefs in the bhAvanA-loka (emotional world) are separate from beliefs about the physical world.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Quotes from Abrahamists upon uncountering heathen art: &lt;a href=&#34;https://storify.com/blog_supplement/encounters-of-barbarous-mlechchas-with-heathen-shr?utm_campaign=website&amp;amp;utm_source=email&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;grudging-proto-polytheism&#34;&gt;Grudging proto-polytheism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One observes in monotheisms a grudging continuation of polytheisms. Examples: &lt;a href=&#34;images/snippets/polytheism_in_monotheism_jewish.jpg&#34;&gt;jewish prayer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;images/snippets/polytheism_in_monotheism_christian.jpg&#34;&gt;catholic prayer&lt;/a&gt;, greek orthodox anathema ritual (where those who see polytheism in worship of icons and such are declared &amp;ldquo;anathema&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In Islam, there are a variety of angels (belief in them is one of the 6 articles of faith), with distinct traits and physical features. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/aaolomi/status/1154103012274520064&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
