<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Abraham myth</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/abraham-myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/abraham-myth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Gnosisinformant/status/1996270952250839434&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not a single primary source from Sumerian, Akkadian, Babylonian, Assyrian, Egyptian, Hittite, Hurrian, Mittani, Canaanite or ANY LANGUAGE at all mentions an Abraham from Ur that travelled to Egypt and met with a pharaoh and then fought wars against kings in Syria &amp;amp; the Levant (which should be easy to find).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Outside of the Bibile, not even Hebrew, Greek or Aramaic texts mention Abraham until Hecataeus of Abdera around 310BCE. And even those fragments from Hecataeus are lost and only come down to us in citations from Josephus and Diodorus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David and Saul</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/david_and_saul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/david_and_saul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source &lt;a href=&#34;https://threads-web.vercel.app/threads/1152304296937099265&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Illuminating Bible passages on how a pagan deserves only deceit, dissimulation and to be taken advantage of - even when he extends help. Even if fellow-Abrahamics are mortal enemies, a Pagan who extends shelter to one never really wins their loyalty or trust.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;david-and-saul&#34;&gt;David and Saul&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The scene: David flees Israelite territory. King Saul is trying to kill him, no matter how much David tries to prove his bona fides. David + 600 soldiers (w/ families) take shelter with Philistine King Achish of Gath - pagans the Israelites hate. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/fGyP041ahB&#34;&gt;https://t.co/fGyP041ahB&lt;/a&gt;) Pagan king Achish grants David a town to settle in, hoping to win favour through hospitality. And perhaps driving a wedge in Israel. Instead, behind his host&amp;rsquo;s back, David and his men sack and massacre nearby pagan settlements - making sure that the king doesn&amp;rsquo;t hear of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flawed souls</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/flawed-souls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/flawed-souls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GhorAngirasa/status/1983905179864035608&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;taintably-perfect&#34;&gt;Taintably perfect?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The obvious but profound implication of this point is that the soteriological end-state claimed by Christianity is intrinsically flawed because it assumes that a perfect soul can be tainted from the without.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To state that the Devil made Adam commit the original sin (and that Christian salvation works because the Devil will be consigned to hell for eternity) is no answer because there must be something intrinsic in Adam’s constitution that allowed him to heed the words of the devil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heroism vs victimhood</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/victimhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/victimhood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1435380362637676544&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1435380362637676544&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only kind of political meta-narrative that exists right now is the victim narrative. Regardless of where people lean politically, most people interpret politics through the lense of victim and oppressor. This explains many facets of the current political discourse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, how did we get here? In the earlier half of the 20th century, western civilization had a relatively positive view of itself. It saw itself as a saviour, a beacon for progress, not as a victim or an oppressor but a hero.+++(5)+++ As the century progressed, this meta-narrative (of western civilization as heroic) was challenged by many events: decolonization, civil rights movements, Vietnam. In turn, the values that held western civilization together for centuries were deconstructed. This is one factor that lead to the proliferation of post-modernism today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monotheism - political consequence</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/monotheism_political-consequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/monotheism_political-consequence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jan Assmann, &amp;ldquo;Monotheism and its Political Consequences&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This border, the distinction between true and false or good and evil with regard to religion is the proper innovation of monotheism&amp;hellip; There were no idols and heathen in the realm of tribal religion and polytheism. The construction of paganism is the single achievement of monotheism, based on the distinction between true and false. Monotheism, therefore, is a religion that blurs boundaries, the boundaries that are expressed or represented by the divinities of polytheism between cities and countries, tribes and nations, day and night, land and sea, love and war, good and evil&amp;ndash; but that also erects a boundary: between true and false, religion and idolatry. Monotheism is, at the same time, exclusive and universalistic. Both tendencies, the exclusive and the universalistic, have political consequences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temple destruction pattern</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/temple-destruction-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/temple-destruction-pattern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Muslims and Christians deliberately chose pagan sites to assert the supremacy of their religion over paganism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Church of the Holy Sepulchre was built atop a Temple of Venus built by Hadrian.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nor is there any evidence that the Temple of Venus was venerated by Christians as the site of Golgotha prior to Helena&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;vision.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Kaaba in Mecca was a pagan shrine with 360 idols.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is no historical evidence that Abraham or Ishmael even existed, let alone that they built the Kaaba in Mecca.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Likewise, the Mexico City Cathedral was built with the stones of the Aztec Templo Mayor.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In other words, two of the holiest sites of Christianity and Islam are rooted in predatory usurpation of pagan sites that was retroactively justified on pseudo-historical grounds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
