<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christianity on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Christianity on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anti-science</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;problems-with-science&#34;&gt;Problems with Science&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;medieval-history&#34;&gt;Medieval History&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The renaissance spirit owes a lot to the pagan revivalist Plethon, whose school was unfortunately subverted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the Middle Ages, the view that the Book of Nature and the Book of Scripture must be harmonious (because they have the same &amp;ldquo;author&amp;rdquo;) led to non-literal interpretations of scripture to conform to empirical data. [??]&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;William of Conch (1100-1154) said: &amp;ldquo;Since the same earth, water and heat continue to exist today, there is no natural reason why new human races are not produced naturally from their interaction. Since we have never seen this happen, there must be some divine prohibition against it.&amp;rdquo; This is an astounding example from medieval times by a Christian theologian who invokes God not to create living things but to prevent them from naturally getting created.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The chruch famously opposed novel scientific ideas of Copernicus and Galelio (whom it forced to recant). We have also seen a 100 year long rejection of the principle of natural selection. Some even opposed the printing press (&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/HwXHBXK.jpg&#34;&gt;IMG&lt;/a&gt;) and mathematics (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pickover/status/769911258699145216&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is a view that the Christian doctrine of causation (especially the separation of primary and secondary causes) helped the birth of modern science. Only a few phenomena, like Jesus&amp;rsquo; resurrection and the initial moment of creation were thought to be directly caused by God (primary causation). Every thing else was caused by secondary (naturalistic) causes which did not require God&amp;rsquo;s constant intervention. God sets creation in motion and then the intrinsic natures of things carry the process forward.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To find out which phenomena are caused directly by God (miracles), it becomes important to understand what the &amp;ldquo;common course of nature&amp;rdquo; is. Only then can deviations from that common course be detected. An investigation into the common course of nature for the discernment of miracles contributed to the development of modern science.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-status&#34;&gt;Current status&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Catholic church&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Accepts the theory of evolution and the big bang theory since around 1950-s. (Francis &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newrepublic.com/article/120025/pope-francis-quotes-evolution-big-bang-are-nothing-celebrate&#34;&gt;quote&lt;/a&gt;) Main question is when God managed to insert a soul into humans.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Miscellaneous American creationists&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reject big bang, the theory of evolution, even human induced global warming as of 2014.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;secularism-sacred-vs-profane-distinction&#34;&gt;Secularism, Sacred vs profane distinction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thoughts on this are &lt;a href=&#34;../../../self-cultivation/rituals/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burial</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/burial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/burial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brébeuf—the tall, pale stranger from the land across the sea—was invited to witness the sacred Wyandot Feast of the Dead. In the ceremony, held at the Wyandot capital of Ossossané, the Wyandot dead were disinterred, reverently cleaned, and placed together in a communal ossuary pit, along with valuable and meaningful material offerings. The Christian priest was greatly impressed by the pagans’ treatment of their dead, and it is perhaps not coincidence that this was the year of Brébeuf’s first great missionary successes.&#xA;&amp;hellip; Whatever good was present at the Ossossané ossuary—where those who had not yet encountered the fullness of Truth honored their dead as best they knew how—is increased a thousandfold in the cemeteries of the residential schools, where baptized Christians were given Christian burials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homosexuality</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/homosexuality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/homosexuality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gay Christians say that the Bible never condemns homosexuality as the word used in Greek for it is “arsenokoitai” which is a new coinage by Paul and only refers to pederasty of Ancient Greece.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/jesus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;Personality&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Below, we talk about the Nicene Jesus. (Gnostic Christ seems have been *much* better. There were other &amp;ldquo;Christ&amp;quot;s too - some say all of them were fictional.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jesus, if he existed, was racist. (As more non-jew converts came in, this was subsumed by a broader out-group hostility.)&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Matthew 15:21-28 and Mark 7:24-30) - &amp;ldquo;Gentile (non-Jew) woman once begged him to cast away the demon that had possessed her daughter&amp;hellip; He cold-heartedly told the woman that only the Jews were his children and that the Gentiles were dogs. He wouldn’t heal a dog. Only then Jesus relented.&amp;rdquo;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://indiafacts.co.in/a-caution-to-hindus-who-think-jesus-is-dharmic-or-a-saint/#.VLEtHTlGjUY&#34;&gt;Kalavai-201501&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=%E0%AE%AE%E0%AE%A4%E0%AF%8D%E0%AE%A4%E0%AF%87%E0%AE%AF%E0%AF%81+15%3A21-28&amp;amp;version=KJV&#34;&gt;verse in KJ bible and translation&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jesus was misogynist. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://indiafacts.co.in/a-caution-to-hindus-who-think-jesus-is-dharmic-or-a-saint/#.VLEtHTlGjUY&#34;&gt;Kalavai-201501&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jesus was an apocalyptic prophet. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://indiafacts.co.in/a-caution-to-hindus-who-think-jesus-is-dharmic-or-a-saint/#.VLEtHTlGjUY&#34;&gt;Kalavai-201501&lt;/a&gt;)&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Early christians prophesied that he will cause a bloody genocide to happen.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;According to The Bible, Jesus would return to the earth holding a sickle in his hand (Revelation 14:14). An angel would tell him that it is time to start a bloody genocide. Another sickle-wielding angel would join Jesus and the duo would start a violent carnage. The blood they spill would cover the ground up to the horses’ bridles in a space of 1,600 furlongs (Revelation 14:15-20). &amp;hellip; According to this contradictory biblical prophecy, Jesus would unleash the might of the sword and hunger to annihilate a fourth of the population (Revelation 6:8).  &amp;hellip; Jesus would then let loose four angels, who would massacre one-third of the remaining population (i.e., 1.75 billion). Jesus won’t take the chill pill yet. He would instead command 200 million fire-breathing horsemen to massacre a third of the survivors. &amp;quot; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://indiafacts.co.in/jesus-christ-impending-genocide/#.VLE2gDlGjUZ&#34;&gt;Kalavai-jesus-genocide&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jesus was not a Yogi because he said &amp;ldquo;Kingdom of God is within you.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot; As Bart Ehrman has shown (Jesus Interrupted: Revealing the Hidden Contradictions in the Bible, pp. 77-78), not only is the Sermon on the Mount a very late interpolation into the Bible but its message is not one of inward perfection as in the Yoga. Its message is apocalyptic; Jesus expected the end of the world to happen very soon. The verse actually means that the coming Kingdom of God is there and present among the Jewish Christians that were his contemporary followers. In this racist teaching, Gentiles are excluded from that kingdom. &amp;ldquo;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://indiafacts.co.in/a-caution-to-hindus-who-think-jesus-is-dharmic-or-a-saint/#.VLEtHTlGjUY&#34;&gt;Kalavai-201501&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The result was a dishonest book, The Kingdom of God is Within You, in which Tolstoy gave the apocalyptic Jesus a complete botox-like makeover and transformed him into a contemplative teacher who sought perfection within as a Hindu yogi does. Many unthinking Hindus, starting with Mahatma Gandhi, have popularized this propagandist story without realizing that it serves to disarm and proselytize unsuspecting  Hindus.&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://indiafacts.co.in/a-caution-to-hindus-who-think-jesus-is-dharmic-or-a-saint/#.VLEtHTlGjUY&#34;&gt;Kalavai-201501&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jesus did not abrogate the troublesome 10 commandments (such as the one against image worship). [Catholic view: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catholic.com/quickquestions/did-jesus-alter-the-commandment-about-observing-the-sabbath&#34;&gt;2015-here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/e96q67P.png&#34;&gt;image&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sects</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/sects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/sects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mormons&#34;&gt;Mormons&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mormon families are similar large.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;fertility&#34;&gt;Fertility&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fertility pattern: Summary from &lt;a href=&#34;http://mormonfertility.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;MF_E15&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. Larger than replacement level numbers of children.   (That is to say significantly higher than 2.1 children per woman, on average).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. Despite widespread use of contraception. This implies that for Mormons family size is usually chosen deliberately. (By contrast, other religious groups with significantly above-replacement fertility do not allow contraception.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3. In a group of people who are more educated than average and economically more successful than average.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slavery</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/slavery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/slavery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;paul&#34;&gt;Paul&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Slaves, obey your human masters with fear and trembling; and do it with a sincere heart, as though you were serving Christ. Do this not only when they are watching you, because you want to gain their approval; but with all your heart do what God wants, as slaves of Christ. Do your work as slaves cheerfully, as though you served the Lord, and not merely human beings.”—Ephesians 6:5-7&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
