<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Atheism on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Atheism on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anti-brAhmaNa</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/anti-brAhmaNa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/anti-brAhmaNa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;manifestations&#34;&gt;Manifestations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;temple-control&#34;&gt;Temple control&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In several states (eg. draviDianists in tamiL nADu), government controls temple administration, and forces dilution and destruction of tradition.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One can reduce their efforts to: &amp;ldquo;What stops a secular Government from appointing a non-Hindu woman who will enter the garbha griha during her monthly periods and offer beef biryani as prasad?&amp;rdquo; (Suren)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;support-for-british&#34;&gt;Support for british&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are not in favour of any measure, which, in operation, is designed, or tends completely, to undermine the influence and authority of the Britishers, who alone, in the present circumstances of India, are able to hold the scales even between creed and class, and to develop that sense of unity and national solidarity, without which India will continue to be a congeries of mutually exclusive and warring groups, without a common purpose and a common patriotism. We are of those who think that in the truest and best interest of India, its government should continue to be conducted on true British principles of justice and equality of opportunity. We are deeply devoted and loyally attached to British rule.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Econo-theism</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/artha-sAdhaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/artha-sAdhaka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;relation-to-local-systems&#34;&gt;Relation to local systems&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;the world has come a long way from the sārthavāha-s of yore who even when wide-ranging did not disrupt the local systems. For instance, in say the Marahaṭṭā country, where we formerly lived, there was the system of the bārā balutedāra-s which has perhaps lasted in some form from the pre-Āryan days of the Harappan civilization. This system comprised of 12 jāti-s who offered essential services for a village. These spanned the entire range from the jāti-s with a low social rank to those with a large component of steppe ancestry and old Āryan descent who were high-ranked. Irrespective of the real or imagined the local issues rising from inter-jāti conflicts, these still for most part worked as a rather cohesive unit for probably at least 1400 years. The sārthavāha operated on top of this system and bore produce across the country and beyond. However, such vaṇij-s did not do anything to interfere disruptively with the system in the villages.&amp;rdquo; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2020/06/08/pandemic-days-the-fizz-is-out-of-the-bottle/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The modern sārthavāha built by the stock market or the internet is mostly a contrasting species. It is clear they have greater reach and rapacity than the old sārthavāha-s but they are also prone to more evil. There is an entire spectrum of the balance of evil they cause to the utility they provide to society.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;evil-social-engineering-schemes&#34;&gt;Evil social engineering schemes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;these idols of society are not purveying the neutral capitalism that the mleccha elite worship but a new unmāda +++(Leftist 0-theism)+++. This, along with their global reach, has allowed that unmāda to attain pandemic proportions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The self-enriching mithyā-kraya-kartṛ Sora +++(Soros)+++ has absolutely nothing useful to offer to the world and a purely evil player.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The vyāpārin Bejha +++(Bezos)+++ offers several useful services for the jana-samudāya but has leveraged the wealth he has accumulated in the process to do evil.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Among the corporations, karṇa-piśācī guggulu +++(Google)+++ might offer some small services of use to the populace but has used its capture of an important resource to further evil.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;A similar situation is seen with the duṣṭa, Jāka the dāraka +++(Twitter Jack)+++: he offers a platform for online advertisement and conversation but has used it to further evil causes and contribute to the demise of freedom of expression. Probably, Mukhagiri also falls in the same category as Jāka the dāraka.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivations&#34;&gt;Motivations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;atonement-for-rapacity&#34;&gt;Atonement for Rapacity&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;They are to a degree conscious that their rapacious actions cause a measure of harm to individuals and the emergent entity known as society which they comprise.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Moreover, in the past the mleccha and mūla-rugṇa sārthavāha-s used to practice what came to be known as capitalism in an unbridled way and they saw that it acquired a bad name.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Like all humans they too subliminally subscribe to the view that they can gain compensatory puṇya by performing acts in support of religion. In the past, the sārthavāha-s in our midst too, keen to acquire puṇya, used to make donations to various deva-prāsāda-s or build new ones themselves (or pāṣaṇdālaya-s).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;subscription-to-0-theisms&#34;&gt;Subscription to 0-theisms&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;This +++(0-theist)+++ version of the unmāda is now the ascendant religion among the employees of or of these very sārthavāha-s themselves. Thus, what has happened is that they seek to earn puṇya by granting endowments for this new abrahma-ruj.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Even if one were not infected fully by this secular mutation of the old unmāda-s, among the lay mleccha-s there is a certain naive econolatory: they worship the faceless market running by its own vrata-s and attribute all human abhyudaya to these magical market forces. They see it as self-correcting and the panacea for all evil — whereas in the past they used see the prathama and dvitīya unmāda-s as the foundation of their well-being they now either additionally or exclusively genuflect towards the miraculous market.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;social-reinforcement&#34;&gt;Social reinforcement&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In this worship of the market, especially given that it is faceless, its purveyors, the vaṇij, naturally become important idols in society.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oppressive system fetish</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/rudhironmAda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/rudhironmAda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;traits&#34;&gt;Traits&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For traits common with other Abe 0-theist maturations, see &lt;a href=&#34;../&#34;&gt;main page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;change-in-perception-of-reality&#34;&gt;Change in perception of reality&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;grievance-focus&#34;&gt;Grievance focus&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Focus on &amp;ldquo;grievance studies&amp;rdquo;. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DdlNIJB9ZVU&#34;&gt;J Lindsay 20&lt;/a&gt;. They seek to warp the perception of reality in terms of oppressors and oppressed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The can spin a favored oppression angle in any situation. Example - &amp;ldquo;White man and Black man walk to a tailor shop. Attend to white person first? Racist. Attend to black person first? Racist because you want to get rid of him.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rooted in marxist concept of &amp;ldquo;conflict theory&amp;rdquo; of fundamental conflict between classes. Could be bourgeoisie vs proletariat or white vs black lives, male patriarchy vs women, hetero-normative straight culture vs sexual minorities.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s now all about having the power to assert that in fact you are powerless, and therefore immune to criticism&amp;rdquo; - RK.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This, of course, runs counter to hindu ethos:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secularism</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/secularism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/secularism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Secularist argument:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;If your religious faith requires you to enforce its tenets on those who are not members of your faith-community, then your religion is incompatible with a free society and society has a right to defend itself against such encroachment.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Secularism, being in some sense &amp;ldquo;softer&amp;rdquo; in appearance to harder anti-theism and Abrahamisms, is insidious and dangerous from the heathen perspective. Hence it merits a separate page.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;alternative-phrases&#34;&gt;Alternative phrases&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternative phrases that helps us understand secularism better&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
