<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The busy Abrahamists</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/MT/2005-12-18_the-busy-abrahamists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/MT/2005-12-18_the-busy-abrahamists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/12/18/the-busy-abrahamists/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I learned today on the web that a certain British satirist AE Housman about whom I know hardly anything said: “In every American there is an air of incorrigible innocence, which seems to conceal a diabolical cunning.” I wonder what prompted him to make such a comment. Perhaps the Indians thought the same of the British even as he was making such comments about his cousins the Americans. We in our youth had a seen a few Anglo-Australian subversionists who had deceptively entered our school. They were like wasps trying to subvert an acorn into a gall and used a certain innocence which seemed truely incorrigible and appeared to innocently ask questions to deride Hindu deities and create doubts in their regard in the minds of the young students. We however, saw through this guise of the sUchin-s and after a protracted struggle had them overthrown. It was great day when the vicious adventurer David was finally sent packing. This white man, a good- for-nothing in his own land, had wormed his way to our school as a teacher, taking advantage of the Indian respect for the White Massas. He treated the Hindus like dirt until our mini-freedom struggle sent him packing. This is just a sample of one the Abrahmisms waging its war on the Hindus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>रोग-परम्परा</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/MT/roga-paramparA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/articles/MT/roga-paramparA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;रोगाद रोगः- इति रोग-परम्परा | को ऽयम रोगः? मानसिकः ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;कत्र रोगस्य जन्म? मरकतानाम उत्तरे पार्श्वे ऽस्मदीयानाम् मितान्नि-नाम-राष्ट्रस्य पश्चिमे।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;अब्रह्मश् च मूषश् च जोषश् चेत्यादीनाम् राक्षस-ग्रहेण ग्रस्त-मनःसु ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तस्मात् प्रेतः शूल-कीलितः ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तदनन्तरं महामदः ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;नवजो रुधिरोन्मादो दाढिक+++(=श्मश्रु)+++-मुखस्य ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तस्माद् इदानींतनो नव्योन्मादः ।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;परस्परं युध्यन्ते+++(न्ति)+++, किं तु धर्मं प्रति तेषां विरोधः संयुक्तः ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;कस्मात्? विधार्म-भावाद्, विपरीत-बुद्ध्या, रोग-तुल्यैकराक्षस-विश्वासाद्, देव-मूर्ति-द्वेषाच् च ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तस्माद् उच्यते म्लेच्छ-मरून्मत्ताभिसंधिः । तस्य बृहद्-रूपं सर्वोन्माद-समायोग-राक्षस-जाल-शम्बरम् । इदं हिन्दूकानाम् परमम् वैरम् ॥&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
