<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Children of revolution transcript</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/articles/children-of-revolution-transcript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/articles/children-of-revolution-transcript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;videoEmbed&#34;  src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HfH18hsrEPU&#34; caption=&#34;Children of the Revolution [talk on UCTV by Yuri Slezkine]&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;intro-to-the-channel&#34;&gt;Intro to the channel&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[0:00]] - [Announcer] This program is presented by University of California Television. Like what you learn? [[0:06]] Help others discover UCTV podcasts by leaving a comment or rating for us in iTunes. [[0:20]] (energetic music)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;intro-to-the-lecture&#34;&gt;Intro to the lecture&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[0:45]] - Hi everybody. I&amp;rsquo;m Margaret Chowning. I&amp;rsquo;m the Chair of the Moses Lectureship Committee. [[0:54]] We and the Graduate Division are pleased to present Yuri Slezkine the fall speaker [[0:59]] in the Bernard Moses Memorial Lecture series. In 1937, University of California President, [[1:06]] Robert Gordon Sproul and the UC Board of Regents established the Bernard Moses Memorial Lectureship [[1:12]] in the Social Sciences. The lectureship honors the memory of the late Bernard Moses, a professor of history [[1:19]] and political science at the University of California from 1875 to 1911 and an emeritus professor [[1:26]] from 1911 until his death in 1930. Professor Moses earned a worldwide reputation [[1:32]] as a pioneer scholar, especially for his contributions to understanding the historical origins of the problems [[1:38]] of the Latin American republics. Professor Moses was also an expert on Philippine history [[1:44]] and he served as a member of the United States Philippine Commission from 1900 to 1904. [[1:51]] Past lecturers have included Herma Hill Kay, Nicholas Riasanovsky, George Lakoff, Kenneth Stampp, [[1:58]] Ken Jowitt, Reinhard Bendix, Robert Scalapino, John Rowe, Woodrow Borah, Carolyn Merchant, [[2:06]] Jean Lave, Emmanuel Saez, Mary Ann Mason and Aihwa Ong. [[2:13]] And now, I&amp;rsquo;d like to say a few words about our lecturer today, Yuri Slezkine. [[2:18]] Appointed the Jane K. Sather Professor of History in 2009, Professor Slezkine has been a member of the UC Berkeley [[2:25]] Department of History since 1992. His numerous and wide-ranging publications [[2:31]] have focused on ethnic minorities in the Soviet Union as well as, Soviet historiography, ethnography [[2:37]] and ethnogenetics. Winner of the 2005 National Jewish Book Award, [[2:43]] among several other prizes, Slezkine&amp;rsquo;s groundbreaking book &amp;ldquo;The Jewish Century&amp;rdquo; [[2:48]] has been translated into seven languages and remains both widely respected and controversial. [[2:55]] Earlier publications include; &amp;ldquo;Arctic Mirrors: Russia and the Small People of the North&amp;rdquo;, [[3:00]] &amp;ldquo;Between Heaven and Hell: the Myth of Siberia in Russian Culture&amp;rdquo; as a co-editor, the article &amp;ldquo;The USSR as a Communal Apartment [[3:09]] or How a Socialist State Promoted Ethnic Particularism&amp;rdquo; and a co-edited volume with Sheila Fitzpatrick [[3:15]] called &amp;ldquo;In the Shadow of Revolution: Life Stories of Russian Women From 1917 to the Second World War&amp;rdquo;. [[3:22]] Professor Slezkine earned his Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Russian Language and Literature from the University of Moscow in 1978. [[3:29]] Departing the USSR in the late 1970s, he worked as a translator in Mozambique and Portugal [[3:35]] before moving to the United States where he was awarded his doctoral degree in History at the University of Texas at Austin in 1989. [[3:43]] Slezkine has been awarded fellowships from Wissenschaftskolleg in Berlin, [[3:50]] the National Endowment for the Humanities, the Hoover Institution and the Guggenheim Foundation. [[3:55]] He&amp;rsquo;s also a member of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. All these honors are testament to the innovation [[4:01]] and creativity of his scholarship. Professor Slezkine&amp;rsquo;s lecture today to quote from the enticing blurb that drew you all here, [[4:09]] explores the private lives of Bolshevik government officials along with their wives, maids, [[4:16]] lovers, children and comrades. Revolutions, Slezkine tells us, devour their parents. [[4:24]] They begin as tragedy and end at home. By framing the Bolshevik Revolution as a family drama, [[4:30]] Slezkine reimagines the story of the Bolsheviks rise. Please join me in welcoming my friend, [[4:37]] Professor Yuri Slezkine. (audience applauds)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>critical in wokeness</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/articles/critical-in-wokeness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/articles/critical-in-wokeness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What makes a woke theory &amp;ldquo;Critical?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding what the woke mean when they use the term &amp;ldquo;critical,&amp;rdquo; and how that differs from the enlightenment liberal notion of &amp;ldquo;critical thinking.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If there was a single word that summed up the thinking at the heart of Critical Social Justice (AKA wokeness) it is the word ‘critical.’ In the academic world Critical Social Justice Theorists have come up with a great number of theories which they call critical: Critical Pedagogy, Critical Race Theory, Critical Queer Theory, Critical Race Pedagogy, Critical Dietetics, Critical Legal Studies, and so on. All of these are “Critical Theories,” and all of these are explicitly concerned with what is commonly called wokeness, or, in the words of Özlem Sensoy and Robin DiAngelo, Critical Social Justice &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (there’s that word ‘critical’ again).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Victimhood advantage</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/articles/victimhood-advantage_cory-clark_Quillette/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/0-theism/articles/victimhood-advantage_cory-clark_Quillette/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://quillette.com/2021/02/27/the-evolutionary-advantages-of-playing-victim/&#34;&gt;Q&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Evolutionary Advantages of Playing Victim&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Victimhood is defined in negative terms: “the condition of having been hurt, damaged, or made to suffer.” Yet humans have evolved to empathize with the suffering of others, and to provide assistance so as to eliminate or compensate for that suffering. Consequently, signaling suffering to others can be an effective strategy for attaining resources. Victims may receive attention, sympathy, and social status, as well as financial support and other benefits. And being a victim can generate certain kinds of power: It can justify the seeking of retribution, provide a sense of legitimacy or psychological standing to speak on certain issues, and may even confer moral impunity by minimizing blame for victims’ own wrongdoings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
