<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Sikhism on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Sikhism on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Drives</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Drives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Drives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;disdain-for-failure-hindu&#34;&gt;Disdain for &amp;ldquo;failure&amp;rdquo; hindu&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sikhism has latent abrahamist tendencies. In a way, it is proto-islamophile-secularism. Same with many baba-isms. See &lt;a href=&#34;../Anti-hindu_patterns/&#34;&gt;anti-hindu patterns page&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;miri-piri&#34;&gt;mIri-pIri&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It aimed to rearm hindus (spiritually and materially) during oppressive Mughal muslim times by emphasizing (even by &amp;ldquo;democratizing&amp;rdquo;) kShatra. In a sense, they revived the Steppe warrior ethos - albeit in a limited sense (lacking in sophistication, and with many unArya tendencies).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;virtual-kin-marker-temorarily-increasing-group-fitness&#34;&gt;Virtual kin marker temorarily increasing group fitness&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this context one could also bring up the case of the pA&lt;del&gt;nchanada-uShnIShamoha. This moha emerged as result of part but not whole of the khilimoha infecting the Hindu population of the pa&lt;/del&gt;nchanada. The result was the emergence of a new recombinant memetic virus, the uShnIShamoha that retained the self-propagating tendencies of the original khilimoha. This infection was very mild in terms of fitness reduction, but provided a strong virtual kin marker that allowed the infected group to prevail and spread at the expense of the Hindus of the pa~nchanada, and also offered protection to the infected against being overrun by the spreading khilimoha. But as its numbers increased its utility as such a virtual kin marker diminished. Nevertheless, it continues to serve this purpose to a degree in new areas colonized by its carriers, such as North America.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hindu view</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/hindu-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/hindu-view/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;General understanding of sikh drives and patterns are explained elsewhere.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;With the emergence of modern Hindutva, the &amp;ldquo;democratization&amp;rdquo; of kShatra by sikhs is superseded (and rendered obsolete) by a better version more consonant with overall Hindu tradition.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Within sikhs, the better traditions (see &lt;a href=&#34;../Pro-hindu_patterns&#34;&gt;pro-hindu patterns&lt;/a&gt; page and &lt;a href=&#34;../sects&#34;&gt;sects&lt;/a&gt; page) merit encouragement.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pro-hindu patterns</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Pro-hindu_patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Pro-hindu_patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-texts&#34;&gt;In texts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;arjun-deva, 5th in line after nAnaka, was pro-veda and pro-smRti. Arjan dev&amp;rsquo;s shabads form the bulk of granth sahib.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;heavy-brahmana-contribution&#34;&gt;Heavy brAhmaNa contribution&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Almost 50% (16/36) of authors of Guru Granth Sahib were Brahmins. This includes the 11 Bhatts and 5 Bhagats (Beni, Jayadeva, Surdas, Ramanand, Parmanand). And before anybody says &amp;ldquo;but oh they were Sikhs&amp;rdquo;. No, they were not. The Bhagats lived before the advent of Sikhism.  The descendants of the families of Bhatts have not accepted Amrit and initiated into Khalsa order.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;identification-as-hindus&#34;&gt;Identification as hindus&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;tegh-bahadur&#34;&gt;Tegh BahAdur&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guru Tegh Bahadur visited the holy Triveni at Prayaga in 1662 CE. This visit is documented in contemporary Bhat Vahi records. Unlike those unpublished &amp;ldquo;bhat vahis&amp;rdquo;, this one was published by Sikh historian Madanjit Kaur (1978). This Bhat Vahi was signed by Guru Tegh Bahadur.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sects</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/sects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/sects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;power-struggle&#34;&gt;Power struggle&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Certain ‘sects’ attempt to gain control &amp;amp; influence the direction of the sangat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SGPC, urban Indian Sikhs &amp;amp; expats are heavily influenced by Tat Khalsa types. These days Taksalis are increasing their influence across these - though there is some admixture or compromise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When H’s see a pic of JSB in a Gurudwara, they ignorantly conclude this is just ‘khalistani’. Actually it indicates a fight between Taksalis and SGPC. Foreign funded Khalis are trying to co-opt JSB and make him a poster boy for their agenda because of the wave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texts</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Texts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/Texts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Guru Granth Sahib&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Japji Sahib&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anand Sahib&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rehras&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kirtan Sohila&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sukhmani Sahib&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Asa di Var&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dasam Granth&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jaap Sahib&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Benti Chaupai&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Amrit Savaiye&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sarbloh Granth&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Varan Bhai Gurdas&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gurdas Vaar (not part of the grantha) supposedly relates the mecca visit tale too.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;acceptance&#34;&gt;Acceptance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;hard core khAlistanis who don&amp;rsquo;t even accept dahsam granth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some problem shabads in the granth sahib come from Kabir.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
