<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digesting Santa Claus</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/articles/2015-12-25_digesting-santa-claus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/articles/2015-12-25_digesting-santa-claus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://agnimaan.wordpress.com/2015/12/25/digesting-santa-claus/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digesting Santa Claus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Santa Claus is a merry character. He grips the minds of children, and the hearts of all sahRdaya-s with his cheer and compassion. Whatever his pagan origins might have been (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ibtimes.com/santa-claus-pagan-origins-5-influences-behind-father-christmas-1736863&#34;&gt;ibtimes&lt;/a&gt;), we pagans have a problem: He is intimately connected with the zombie cult. Indeed the zombie bastard child is said to have burdened the earth on the santa claus day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luckily, we hindu-s have had long experience with borrowing and hijacking of our deities as part of the competition amongst our orthodox and heterodox traditions. All one needs do is “expand” a few legends. So, lets “understand” santa claus in our terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Augustine on digestion</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/articles/augustine_on_digestion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/articles/augustine_on_digestion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/maa_bhaishiiH/status/1827749592550768951&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;St Augustine on Christians appropriating Greco-Roman philosophy while abandoning their gods. He be like: &amp;ldquo;It is perfectly OK - when the Israelites left Egypt, they took the gold from Egypt but not the idols. Similarly, we can take the philosophy and abandon the idols. Actually, it is we Christians who deserve to be in possession of these valuable knowledge - these pagans are having unlawful possession of the knowledge that they don&amp;rsquo;t deserve anyways as they are using it to worship devils.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inculturation prohibition</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/articles/inculturation-prohibition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/articles/inculturation-prohibition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/threadreaderapp/status/1918319861207347611&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The worship of the lord like the posted above has been prohibited by the Holy See! This son is actually going against many decrees, doctrines and directives still are in force. I am making a small list with all the references given.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This kind of worship is against the Code of Canon Law (1917)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Canon 1258: Prohibited Catholics from participating in non-Catholic religious ceremonies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Canon 1399: Forbade the reading of books promoting superstition, divination, magic, and other practices contrary to Catholic doctrine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pope Pius XI. (1937) in Mit Brennender Sorge detailed Encyclical condemning neopagan ideologies and ordered Christians never to adopt any pagan festivals, ideologies in fact he said &amp;ldquo;Nothing can be useful&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Putting Lord in the middle of pagan festival is highest sacrilege and those who do this will not be allowed at St Peter&amp;rsquo;s gate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
