<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bin Salman 2022</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/bin-salmAn-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/bin-salmAn-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mohammed bin Salman on Iran, Israel, US and future of Saudi Arabia: Full transcript&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Al Arabiya English&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Saudi Arabia’s Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman discussed the future of the Kingdom and its economy, as well as foreign policy stances involving Iran, Israel and the US in a wide-ranging interview with The Atlantic published on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is the full transcript:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been coming back here since 2019. Every time it&amp;rsquo;s a little more different, more modern, more advanced, 2030 gets closer, and it gets a little bit more like Dubai, even a little bit more like America. Do you think Saudi Arabia will become less Saudi and more like the rest of the world?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cannibalism</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/cannibalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/cannibalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amir Mahmud in his work Habib al-Siyar writes that after the battle of Merv, the body of Shaybani Khan was found under a pile of slain Uzbeks, having died of suffocation. The qizilbashs severed his head and then cannibalized him in an act of devotion towards Shah Isma&amp;rsquo;il. Shah Isma&amp;rsquo;il latter turned Shaybani Khan&amp;rsquo;s skull into a jewelled drinking goblet—an old tradition of the steppe nomads, from the times of Xiongnu—and gifted it to Babur while sending his other body parts all over the empire to be put on display.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christian-heresy</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/christian-heresy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/christian-heresy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1590639848762720258.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to get to grips with what Mohammed peddled to his audience, and fully comprehend original Islamic theology (prior to the Hadith retcons), you have to understand that Islam began as a Christian heresy. Once you realise this, it makes more sense. Let&amp;rsquo;s dip into that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Islamic tradition claims Mohammed battled polytheistic pagan idol-worshippers. That&amp;rsquo;s likely fiction. Historically, Mohammed vied with Jews and Christians, which is why the Quran talks about their beliefs so much, whereas it doesn&amp;rsquo;t delve into supposed &amp;ldquo;Meccan&amp;rdquo; paganism. To run his scam, and persuade Jews and Christians to follow his new religion instead of their existing ones, Mohammed had to depict both Judaism and Christianity as flawed, and Islam as a celestial correction Allah had sent down for humanity to follow. He did this via Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>fitness-effect rjrasva</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/fitness-effect_rjrasva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/fitness-effect_rjrasva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;higher-fitness-when-among-kufrs&#34;&gt;Higher fitness when among kufrs&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When Mohammedans r embedded in a population enthralled by limp ideologies liberalism, feminism, objectivism etc. It can actually enhance /1   the fitness of a # of them &amp;amp; their group. &lt;strong&gt;Kufr produces wealth for them to produce kids&lt;/strong&gt;, or they may be inspired to acts of jihad like /2   capturing kufr women &amp;amp; produce kids thru them. (Parallel in early christianity -&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amantius offered no guarantee at first that the interview with Eudoxia would come off.237 This proved to be only the first hurdle to the prelates&amp;rsquo; ambitions, for emperor Arcadius hesitated to crush the Hellenic cults of Gaza for fear that revenue collection there would suffer. Mark the Deacon gives the gist of Arcadius&amp;rsquo; reply to Eudoxia after she confronted him with bishop Porphyrius&amp;rsquo; petition. Porphyrius got this bit of information directly from Amantius himself:238&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hadith science flaws</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/hadith-science-flaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/hadith-science-flaws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/YetAnthrStudent/status/1790715415930478748&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After years of studying hadith science, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to the conclusion that isnad science is indeed a joke, isnads are essentially meaningless—an illusion. Here are a few reasons why:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-Transformation of Reports: Interrupted (mursal/mawquf) reports are often transformed into marfu&amp;rsquo; by later transmitters, with selection bias acting as a canonization tool for reports with connected isnads.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;-Widespread Tadlis: Tadlis (concealing true sources) was practiced by nearly everyone in the second generation and some companions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>halAl economy</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/halAl-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/halAl-economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1542784913362915328.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What comes in your mind when you hear the word &amp;lsquo;Halal&amp;rsquo; ? How Halal became the &amp;lsquo;Economic Jihad&amp;rsquo; tool of Islam worldwide ? This will be a rather longish thread in parts. Bear with me and do read &amp;amp; share all parts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How big is the Halal Economy?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;USA : nominal GDP $20.58 trillion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;India: nominal GDP $2.94 trillion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Halal Economy: $3.6 + trillion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Halal&amp;rdquo; is an Arabic word that was in existence even before Islam, same like the word &amp;ldquo;Allah&amp;rdquo;. Halal means &amp;ldquo;permissible/ legitimate&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Jayaz&amp;rdquo;. In Islam, things or doings are either Halal or Haraam. There is no Grey in between. The word Halal has seen three revolutions, Before Islam, After the Origin of Islam, After World war 2. Currently, the 4th revolution is what we are going to see and the most devastating one (devastating to the non-halal economy).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>islamic-state-apocalypse</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/islamic-state-apocalypse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/islamic-state-apocalypse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2015/03/what-isis-really-wants/384980/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What ISIS Really Wants&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Islamic State is no mere collection of psychopaths. It is a religious group with carefully considered beliefs, among them that it is a key agent of the coming apocalypse. Here’s what that means for its strategy—and for how to stop it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March 2015 Issue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the Islamic State?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Where did it come from, and what are its intentions? The simplicity of these questions can be deceiving, and few Western leaders seem to know the answers. In December, The New York Times published confidential comments by Major General Michael K. Nagata, the Special Operations commander for the United States in the Middle East, admitting that he had hardly begun figuring out the Islamic State’s appeal. “We have not defeated the idea,” he said. “We do not even understand the idea.” In the past year, President Obama has referred to the Islamic State, variously, as “not Islamic” and as al-Qaeda’s “jayvee team,” statements that reflected confusion about the group, and may have contributed to significant strategic errors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kerala perumAL mosque</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/kerala-perumal-mosque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/kerala-perumal-mosque/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Chera Perumal who supposedly built this mosque ruled during the 12th century, that&amp;rsquo;s more than 500 years later than this imaginary date.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scholarship disawoves it, the most radical date is Kugle and Margariti (2017) who date the emergence of the legend to 1540 - 1580, while the most conservative estimate from Prange (2018) places it between the 1100s and 1300s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is for the legend, the mosque itself has never properly had a date assigned by scholarly examination as far as I know, but it can&amp;rsquo;t have been too much older than the tale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lebanon islamification</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/lebanon-islamification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/lebanon-islamification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thread by @PankajSaxena84 on &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1536565306734542853.html&#34;&gt;Thread Reader App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How Lebanon became a Muslim majority country overnight&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Lessons Hindus can learn from the Lebanese Civil War&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Unfinished Agendas of Political Islam – Case 1 – Lebanon&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this thread we see how political Islam conquers a non-Muslim country even in the contemporary age.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is not allowed for a Muslim to live in a country ruled by a non-Muslim. That is because non-Muslims are necessarily inferior to Muslims in the Islamic scheme of things. If they actually do they should strive to convert that country into a Muslim majority country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MathurA massacre</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/mathurA-massacre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/mathurA-massacre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/satoverma/status/1892237926416679112&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A first person narrative of the mass killing of Hindus of Mathura by Ahmed Shah Abdali in 1757. These narratives were written by Ghulam Hasan Samin and translated into English by William Irvine in the vol. 36 of Indian Antiquary in 1907. The details are gory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Mathura, they did mass scale killing of Hindu ascetics. They killed cows as well and tied the severed head of the cows around the neck of killed ascetics in a way that dead cow&amp;rsquo;s head touched the mouth of slain ascetics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pagan festivals</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/pagan-festivals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/pagan-festivals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/avatans/status/1876086207551058410&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why Jihadists Wage War on Christmas (and Other Holidays)?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Islamists… despise any holiday not sanctioned by Islam.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Islamic theologians of the Middle Ages set out the general approach. Ibn Taymiya (1263-1328) argued that joining non-Muslims in their festivals is equivalent to “agreeing to infidelity.” His student Ibn al-Qayyim (1292-1350) specified that congratulating non-Muslims on their holidays “is a greater sin than congratulating them for drinking wine, having illegal sexual intercourse, and so on.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sayyidification</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/sayyidification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/sayyidification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Twitter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The tendency that we see among many Muslims in the Indian subcontinent today to identify more with Islamic traditions from the Middle East than the culture they are from has its roots in the colonial period. In the medieval period, except for elite ashrafs, the people from +lower castes/ classes who converted to Islam often retained aspects of their Hindu culture. The fashioning of Muslim political identity began in earnest from 19th century.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sirhindi&#39;s legacya and Turkey</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/rabbAni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/rabbAni/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1448835563243646986&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1448835563243646986&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sirhindi&#34;&gt;Sirhindi&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imam Rabbani (Ahmad Sirhindi)&lt;/em&gt; is considered the second greatest Islamic theologian after &lt;em&gt;Imam Ghazali&lt;/em&gt;. They both fused the current state of Sufism back into ulema-centered Islam. Imam Rabbani popularized the theology of “wahdat ash-shahood” - oneness of witnessing. This is a lame misappropriation of Vishishtadvaita, whose Ramanandi proponents were active in the area around where Sirhindi grew up. This reductionistic plagiarism was subhanallah’ed. Just as “wahdat al-wajood” is a reductionistic image of Advaita, Rabbani’s school is of Vishishtadvaita.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terror support</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/terror-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/terror-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/tabrezhasan1122/status/1925427060341940420&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quran preaches if anyone kills an innocent human being it’s as though as he killed whole humanity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Muslims always quote Quran 5:32 leaving out the small detail: It does not apply to transgressor and according to Islam all Non-Muslims are transgressors cause they disapprove of Allah&amp;rsquo;s final msg.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We decreed upon the Children of Israel that whoever kills a soul unless for a soul or for corruption [done] in the land - it is as if he had slain mankind entirely. And whoever saves one - it is as if he had saved mankind entirely. And our messengers had certainly come to them with clear proofs. Then indeed many of them, [even] after that, throughout the land, were transgressors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wrongful-death-compensation-disparity</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/wrongful-death-compensation-disparity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/wrongful-death-compensation-disparity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;rules in the modern state of Saudi Arabia, in particular, the rules governing the measure of wrongful death damages.45 According to the Indian Consulate in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, the families of Indian expatriates working in the Kingdom can claim wrongful death compensation pursuant to a schedule of fixed amounts. However, the amounts vary depending on the victim&amp;rsquo;s religious convictions and gender. If the victim is a Muslim male, his family can claim SR100,000. But if the victim is a Christian or Jewish male, the family can only claim half that amount, namely SR50,000. Further, if the victim belongs to another faith group, such as Hindu, Sikh, or Jain, his family can claim only approximately SR6,667. The family of a female victim can claim half the amount allowed for her male co-religionist. 46 Arguably, it seems that Saudi Arabia patterns its wrongful death compensatory regime on early Hanbali rules of tort liability. For example, premodern Muslim jurists held that the diyya or wrongful death compensation for a free Muslim male was one hundred camels.47 But if the victim is a Jew or Christian male, his family could only claim a percentage of that amount. The Shafi&amp;rsquo;is held that the family was entitled to one-third of what a free Muslim male&amp;rsquo;s family would receive.48 But the Malikis and Hanbalis granted them one-half of what a Muslim&amp;rsquo;s family could obtain.49 Furthermore, Sunni and Shi&amp;rsquo;a jurists held that if the victim was a Magian (majus), his family received even less, namely 1/15th of what a free Muslim male was worth.50 Importantly, 1/15th of SR100,000 is approximately SR6667, the amount a Hindu, Sikh, or Jain&amp;rsquo;s family can claim under current Saudi law.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yusuf on bohras</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/yusuf_on_bohras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/islam/articles/yusuf_on_bohras/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From : Yusuf Unjhawala&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;origin&#34;&gt;Origin&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dawoodi Bohra belief system comes from the Fatimids of Egypt. Fatimids were Ismaili Shias who ruled Egypt and North Africa for about 300 years (900-1200AD). There were splits prior to the Fatimids and during the Fatimids. One branch of the Fatimids are the Nizaris (today&amp;rsquo;s Aga Khanis), other is Mustali which are Bohras.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the reign of Mustansir (circa 1000 AD - an Imam for the Bohras) missionaries were sent to Gujarat. They managed to convert a few. Thats how it started. The early converts were not known as Bohras. That wouldve happened later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
