<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;sAtvata TW on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/sAtvataTW/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;sAtvata TW on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/sAtvataTW/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blasphemy</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/sAtvataTW/blasphemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/sAtvataTW/blasphemy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Saatvata/status/2005109864989949980&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Catholics, Lutherans, Presbyterians, et al. could not even tolerate Mormons and Anabaptists who worship Jesus Christ. Why would they tolerate pagans? Countless people were burnt at the stake for &amp;ldquo;blaspheming Christ&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;blaspheming the Holy Spirit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Calvin and the Geneva Consistory had the Spanish physician Servetus burnt at the stake (indirectly via magistrate) because he likened the Trinity to three-headed Cerberus (one of the &amp;ldquo;Hounds of Hades&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Freedom of speech implies freedom to criticize religion and this includes criticism of even the most intolerant religions like Christianity and Islam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History satire</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/sAtvataTW/history-satire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/sAtvataTW/history-satire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The existence of archangel Gabriel is historically accurate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Parthenogenesis in humans is historically accurate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jesus being born before 4 BC (&amp;ldquo;in the days of king Herod&amp;rdquo;) and after 6 AD (during the first census when Quirinius was governor of Syria) is historically accurate, despite these dates being mutually exclusive by approximately a decade.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A universal census requiring people to travel to ancestral towns, an event unattested in Roman administrative records, is historically accurate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Joseph and Mary leaving Nazareth and arriving at a city which just so happens to have the same name as the Messianic tribe mentioned in Micah 5:2 is historically accurate and in no way suggests retroactive Messianic prophecy fulfillment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Babylonian wise men divining the birth of a Jewish messiah via astrology (a practice condemned elsewhere in the Bible, BTW) and traveling to an obscure Judean backwater in alleged fulfillment of the Seventy Weeks prophecy of Daniel is historically accurate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Herod ordering the slaughter of all infants in Judea is historically accurate, notwithstanding the absence of any extrabiblical attestation from any contemporary historians who meticulously recorded Herod&amp;rsquo;s far smaller atrocities.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;None of this is legendary. None of this is messianic or theological propaganda. This is all history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human culpability in jesus killing</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/sAtvataTW/human-culpability_jesus-killing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/sAtvataTW/human-culpability_jesus-killing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;??&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They do not accept that Christianity is an apocalyptic Jewish sect whose founder was killed by the Romans for rebellion and was only later reworked into a separate religion by Peter and Paul. That is the &amp;ldquo;secular&amp;rdquo; interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;jewish-killing&#34;&gt;Jewish killing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They (Christians) believe the Biblical narrative in which Jesus was God and was &amp;ldquo;killed&amp;rdquo; neither by the Jews and Romans. In the Biblical narrative, the Jewish pharisees and high priest demand that Jesus be crucified even though Pilate saw no fault in Jesus. Even when given the option to pardon a criminal, the Jews favored the murder/bandit Barabbas over Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian history</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/sAtvataTW/indian-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/sAtvataTW/indian-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;pre-nicene-romances&#34;&gt;Pre-Nicene romances&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prior to the 5th century, we basically have pseudo-historical romance (Acts of Thomas), hearsay from Eusebius&amp;rsquo; (Hebrew copy of Gospel of Matthew discovered by Pantaneus) and the Chronicle of Seert (a 9th-11th century text claiming that David of Basra evangelized India in the 4th century).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-nicene&#34;&gt;Post-Nicene&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All Indian Christian churches hold post-Nicene theological views which derive from an earlier church in Ctesiphon or Nisibis which in turn derives from an earlier church in Edessa/Osrhoene. Indian Christian liturgy is post 4th century and Indian Christians first show up in the historical record around the 6th century AD (Cosmas Indicopluestes).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus return</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/sAtvataTW/jesus-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/sAtvataTW/jesus-return/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Saatvata/status/1986309315083338227/history&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Bible makes no mention of Jesus&amp;rsquo; return in 2,000 years. There is no verse anywhere in the Old or New Testament where Jesus (or anyone else) says he will return in 2,000 years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;2,000&amp;rdquo; year apocalypse is a relatively recent belief (e.g. William Miller&amp;rsquo;s prediction of a 1844 &amp;ldquo;apocalypse&amp;rdquo; based on his intepretation of &amp;ldquo;days&amp;rdquo; in Daniel 8:14 as &amp;ldquo;years,&amp;rdquo; John Nelson Darby&amp;rsquo;s theory of &amp;ldquo;dispensations,&amp;rdquo; etc.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
