<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mormons: H appraisal</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/an-appraisal-about-mormonism-from-the-hindu-standp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/an-appraisal-about-mormonism-from-the-hindu-standp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: A 2015-08-31 article on the net.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An appraisal about mormonism from the hindu standpoint: benefits, cohesion, barriers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following is from a dialog amonga few friends about the LSD (sorry LDS) church.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;priesthood-levels&#34;&gt;Priesthood levels&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my mid-twenties, I had been baptised in the LDS Church. I was actively involved with various other religious groups at the time, and this I told my Mormon teachers who had been giving me lessons for a few months, but they honestly said, “Baptism is only the beginning, not the end. It only qualifies you to continue to study our theory and sacraments.” So I did. After baptism, one is automatically inducted into the first level “Aaronic priesthood”. Based on proven abilities and completed sacraments, one can rise up to higher priesthoods such as Melchizedek, etc. In many ways, the LDS Church is modeled on Freemasonry or other esoteric schools with their distinction betwen neophytes,&#xA;hierophants, adepts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abe and moonies</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/abe_moonies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/abe_moonies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shinzo Abe’s Assassin and Japan’s Complicated Spirituality&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The country’s so-called new religions have caused a disproportionate amount of turmoil.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By Hiroko Yoda&lt;br&gt;&#xA;July 26, 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Portrait of Shinzo Abe seen during ceremony at the Japan Embassy in Bangkok.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Japan is not widely known for religious extremism or gun violence, and yet Abe’s association with the Unification Church was his murderer’s apparent motive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The killing of the former Prime Minister of Japan, Shinzo Abe, on July 8th, sent shock waves rippling across Japan and the globe. Even after stepping down as Prime Minister, in the summer of 2020, owing to health issues, Abe was that rarest of presences on the Japanese political scene: an internationally recognizable face, even a celebrity. His hawkish brand of conservatism divided Japan and infuriated many leaders in the region, but endeared him to others, most famously Donald Trump. And, as the single longest-serving prime minister in Japan’s history, he remained, in many ways, the country’s face to the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bethlehem star</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/bethlehem-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/bethlehem-star/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://phys.org/news/2025-12-star-bethlehem-comet-ancient-chinese.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Star of Bethlehem might have actually been a comet described in an ancient Chinese text&lt;br&gt;&#xA;by Krystal Kasal, Phys.org&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Star of Bethlehem&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Image generated by the editorial team using DALL·E for illustrative purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many researchers have spent decades attempting to decode biblical descriptions and link them to verifiable historical events. One such description is that of the Star of Bethlehem—a bright astronomical body that was said to lead the Magi to Jesus shortly after his birth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese-christian-deceit</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/chinese-christian-deceit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/chinese-christian-deceit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1594296228702986241.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pretty hilarious - and kind of disturbing - to read how the first Christian missionaries to China presented Catholicism so the Chinese wouldn’t find it too unfamiliar. E.g. as Europeans they presented themselves as Indian monks following a special strand of Buddhism. A short 🧵. This is all extracted from this book 🔽, &amp;ldquo;A Jesuit in the Forbidden City&amp;rdquo;, by Ronnie Po-chia Hsia on the life of Matteo Ricci.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas origin</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/christmas-origin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/christmas-origin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1465979583384195076&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1465979583384195076&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christians prob settled on Dec 25 for Xmas b/c they were obsessed with calculating Jesus’ conception, birth, and death based on the vague info in the Gospels. March 25 (the Roman vernal equinox) became popular for his crucifixion, Dec 25 (the winter solstice) for his birth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;equinox-for-crucifixion-day&#34;&gt;Equinox for crucifixion day&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early 3rd c. evidence demonstrates that these chronographers started to settle on March 25 as the crucifixion day. Source: an “Easter calculation calendar” that likely was produced by the priest Hippolytus. Scholar @SarahEBond has some excellent photographs of replicas of this artifact &lt;a href=&#34;https://sarahemilybond.com/2018/03/31/anno-domini-computational-analysis-antisemitism-and-the-early-christian-debate-over-easter/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conversion causes</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/rjrasva__conversion-causes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/rjrasva__conversion-causes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what &amp;ldquo;ground work&amp;rdquo; these 2 sanghis have done but they seem to have no touch with reality &amp;amp; repeating talking pts they get in their bauddhik sessions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been through almost every call recording &amp;amp; video interviews of ex pretas by Shivashakti, reasons for preta success mentioned are family problems like disease,&#xA;alcoholism, &amp;amp; finances sometimes. Usually disease or some other family problem are mentioned. Not even SC callers have mentioned jati discrimination as the reason+++(5)+++. That&amp;rsquo;s what u get when u do actual ground work like Shivashakti.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>God of israel</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/god_of_israel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/god_of_israel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/maa_bhaishiiH/status/1780084106501702039&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At many places in the Old Testament (Jewish bible), God calls himself &amp;ldquo;the God of Israel&amp;rdquo; . 203 of them are given in the thread quoted below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was the apostle Paul who,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;after his supposed vision,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;proclaimed that the salvation from this God of Israel was open to everyone through faith in Christ.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Christians proclaimed that they are the new Israel,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;not by ethnicity but by faith in the God of Israel and his so called &amp;ldquo;son&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human animal killing</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/human-animal-killing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/human-animal-killing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Rjrasva on TW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Besides the well known witch killings (a form of human sacrifice), some cat burning for fun by Deus Vult Londoners of 1677&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://google.com/books/edition/Remember_Remember/hYYSKgMpAxIC?hl=en&amp;amp;gbpv=1&amp;amp;dq=in+the+city+with+mighty+bonfires+and+the+burning+of+a+most+costly+pope+,+carried+by+four+persons+in+divers+habits&amp;amp;pg=PA98&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday the coronation of Queen Elizabeth was solemnized in the city with mighty bonfires and the burning of a most costly pope, carried by four persons in divers habits, and the effigies of two devils whispering in his ears, his belly filled with live cats who squalled most hid- eously as soon as they felt the fire; the common saying all the while was the language of the pope and the devil in a dialogue betwixt them. A tirce [42 gallons] was set out before the Temple gate for the common people. Mr Langthorne saith he is very confident the pageantry cost forty pounds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jesus-racism</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/jesus-racism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/jesus-racism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GhorAngirasa/status/1622404897865089024/photo/1&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;source&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;24And from thence he arose, and went into the borders of Tyre and Sidon, and entered into an house, and would have no man know it: but he could not be hid. 25For a certain woman, whose young daughter had an unclean spirit, heard of him, and came and fell at his feet: 26The woman was a Greek, a Syrophenician by nation; and she besought him that he would cast forth the devil out of her daughter. 27But Jesus said unto her, Let the children first be filled: for it is not meet to take the children&amp;rsquo;s bread, and to cast it unto the dogs. 28And she answered and said unto him, Yes, Lord: yet the dogs under the table eat of the children&amp;rsquo;s crumbs. 29And he said unto her, For this saying go thy way; the devil is gone out of thy daughter. 30And when she was come to her house, she found the devil gone out, and her daughter laid upon the bed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Krishna 1906</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/krishna_1906/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/krishna_1906/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A readable Thread by @HindooHistory&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blue Grass Blade, 1906 &amp;ldquo;HINDOO DELIVERS HOT ROAST&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Christian Missionary Work In India&amp;ndash; Finds More Caste Exclusion in American Than In His Own Country HITS BACK WITH BITTER AND STINGING WIT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It took the naked savages to literally dine off broiled missionary, but the following from Anaconda (Montana) Standard gives an account of a figurative roast reported from Butte. The report, which explains itself, is follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nAzi-s vs Christ</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/nAzis-vs-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/nAzis-vs-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nazis smeared excrement on church altars and church doors, desecrated shrines, and threw statues of saints into dung piles; and when synagogues were not available to  attack and loot, churches were often the target with Nazis yelling:  &amp;lsquo;Down with Christians and Jews!&amp;rdquo; -  The Nazi War on Christianity by Bruce Walker, p. 49.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What Bolshevism is achieving today on the materialist and technical level, Christianity had achieved on the metaphysical level. When the Crown sees the throne totter, it needs the support of the masses. It would be better to speak of Constantine the Traitor and Julian the Loyal than of Constantine the Great and Julian the Apostate.+++(5)+++ What the Christians wrote against the Emperor Julian is approximately of the same calibre as what the Jews have written against us.+++(4 Conceit!)+++ The writings of the Emperor Julian, on the other hand, are products of the highest wisdom.+++(5)+++ If humanity took the trouble to study and understand history, the resulting consequences would have incalculable implications. One day ceremonies of thanksgiving will be sung to Fascism and National Socialism for having preserved Europe from a repetition of the triumph of the underworld.&amp;rdquo; - Adolf Hitler, January 2, 1942.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On bAbA bhAratI</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/on-bAbA-bhAratI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/on-bAbA-bhAratI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vivekananda and his fellow Ramakrishna disciples were not the only ones who come to America in the aftermath of the Parliament. Published in the St Louis Republic in 1902, the clip below is first hand account written by journalist turned Vaishnava missionary Baba Bharati.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Republic, 1902&lt;br&gt;&#xA;He was the Original of Rudyard Kipling&amp;rsquo;s Holy Man in &amp;lsquo;Kim&amp;rsquo;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Baba Bharati, from India, has arrived in New York to make converts to his faith, which is &amp;lsquo;Love for all Men.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orphism comparison</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/orphism-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/orphism-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Saatvata/status/1975504140861083885&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;similarity-summary&#34;&gt;Similarity Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Theme&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Orphism&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Christianity&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Divine Victim&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Dionysus Zagreus, dismembered by the Titans&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Christ, crucified by humanity&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Divine Innocence&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;The child-god torn apart unjustly&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;The sinless Son of God unjustly&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Human Complicity&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Humanity descends from the guilty Titans&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Humanity bears God&amp;rsquo;s image, wounded by sin&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Divine Element in Humans&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Humans contain Dionysus&amp;rsquo; spark divine essence&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Humans bear God&amp;rsquo;s image&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Goal of Salvation&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Purify Titanic nature and reawaken divine essence&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Redeem fallen nature and restore divine image&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Means of Communion&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Consuming Dionysus&amp;rsquo; essence (wine = blood)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Consuming Christ&amp;rsquo;s body and blood (wine = blood)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Final Destiny&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Return to divine unity (theosis)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Eternal life with God (eschatology)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;killed-and-consumed-deity&#34;&gt;Killed and consumed deity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the core of Christianity is a belief in substitutionary atonement through the consumption of the flesh and blood of a risen savior deity. This risen savior deity is the &amp;ldquo;Lamb of God who takes away the sin of the world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rice bag</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/rice-bag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/rice-bag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lafcadio Hearn reports on June 1, 1893 about Christians targeting Japanese kids for conversion by giving them money &amp;amp; trying to buy land (many Japanese even those in poverty refused to sell) to set up missions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Postwar Japan: Japanese who did convert to Christianity were derisively called &amp;ldquo;rice Christians&amp;rdquo; by other Japanese. The derogatory nickname implied that missionaries provided material or financial benefit as inducement to converts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taiwan - people at that time called Catholciism &amp;ldquo;powdered milkism&amp;rdquo; (naifenjiao) or &amp;ldquo;flourism&amp;rdquo; (mianfenjiao).77 And the Church was known as the &amp;ldquo;flour church.&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; Although most of Taiwan&amp;rsquo;s population rejoiced in its newfound prosperity&amp;hellip; not everyone on the island found these processes comforting. Protestant missionaries&amp;hellip; discovered that economic progress was hindering Christian expansion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steines apologetics</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/steines_apologetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/steines_apologetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Burning alive the missionary&amp;rsquo;s two sons (aged 10 and 6) does not help the H cause, imho. (Some claim that DS was not guilty, but the ppl supporting him on the web assume that he was and celebrate him for it.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are the exact events detailed somewhere? I imagine Graham would&amp;rsquo;ve been warned to get out (and face death) or his vehicle would be burned with kids. Did he reject possibility of kids being spared and keep them inside? Christian martyrdom fetish is why Japs invented tsurushi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>White peril</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/white-peril/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/white-peril/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1518614721527631872.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;#HindooHistory #BabaBharati&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Los Angeles Herald, 1906&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;WHITE PERIL&amp;rsquo; IN WAY OF WEST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bharati Reverses Accepted Theories&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Says the East Has Long Had a Civilization of Which the Occident Knows Nothing and its Life is a Mystery&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the publication of the &amp;lsquo;Letters of a Chinese Official&amp;rsquo; some time ago, people have begun to wonder whether the view taken by the author might not have some real foundation. The &amp;lsquo;Replies&amp;rsquo; of Mr. Bryan served but little to enlighten the ever-growing question; and now comes Baba Bharati of this city, who is an article in the current issue of the &amp;lsquo;Light of India,&amp;rsquo; not only corroborates the sentiments expressed by the first writer, but adds thereto.  He holds that the reason the Occidental understands so little of his Oriental brother is he has never tried. He says:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>yajurveda forgery</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/yajurveda-forgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/articles/yajurveda-forgery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1447876397251248133&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1447876397251248133&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jesuit missionaries in the 18th century forged a text in French they called the &amp;ldquo;Ezourvedam&amp;rdquo; and passed it as an authentic translation of the Yajurveda from Sanskrit by a learned Brahmana. The text showed how the original doctrine of the Brahmins was monotheism &amp;amp; anti-idolatry! This Ezourvedam was given to Voltaire and for the better part of 50 years, it lent the impression to European intellectuals that the religion of the Indians had also opposed idolatrous superstitions at the start. Issac Newton himself thought the Brahmins of India are direct descendants of Abraham and even the word Brahmana comes from Abrahamans (sons of Abraham) and that Abraham instructed the Brahmins in worship of one god without images &amp;amp; sent them to the east. This influenced Voltaire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
