<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>amritpAl-singh-rise</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/articles/amritpAl-singh-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/articles/amritpAl-singh-rise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rise of Amritpal Singh in Punjab and the striking similarities with Bhindranwale&amp;rsquo;s early&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Updated: 26 December, 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;waris-punjab-de&#34;&gt;Waris Punjab De&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amritpal Singh Khalsa, a Sikh preacher and current chief of late actor Deep Sidhu’s organisation ‘Waris Punjab De’, is walking across the state under the banner of ‘Khalsa Vaheer’ or ‘Khalsa March’. The pro-Khalistani preacher took over the organisation after Sidhu’s demise in an accident on February 15, 2022. Sidhu formed ‘Waris Punjab De’ in September 2021 with the aim to “protect the rights of Punjab and raise social issues”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hazUrIs</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/articles/hazUrIs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/articles/hazUrIs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The information in this article was taken from the Sarbloh Website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The author is very open and frank about the historicl tensions between the Sanatan orientation of Hazoori Sikhs and the Tat Khalsa (these tensions stretch back to approximately 1925).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The author is also critical of the influence of Punjabi/Jat Sikhs, with this critique also having historical roots in northern India of the 19th Century.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also there are exquisite images in the original article that do not reproduce either as image files or in pdf format. So view those pictures and Please Visit the Site Sanatan Sikhi&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India hindu rejection</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/articles/india-hindu-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/articles/india-hindu-rejection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1824700759222386921.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;divorcing-phenomenon&#34;&gt;Divorcing phenomenon&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lot of Sikhs bet on the strategy of completely divorcing themselves from the bad reputation and stereotypes of India by calling themselves “Punjabis, Sikhs” and believing in that exceptionalism. Indians obviously took glee in it when North Americans started rejecting this shtick.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;refuge-of-mediocrity&#34;&gt;Refuge of mediocrity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m also a Punjabi, but why should I do Punjabi exceptionalism? If I really want to divorce myself from India’s bad reputation, then who cares about ethnicity? I should just bring in my caste (Khatri) which is responsible for most of Punjabi history as well as being elite human capital in modernity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jai-singh and bangla-sAhib</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/articles/jai-singh_bangla-sAhib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/articles/jai-singh_bangla-sAhib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1640006460204777472.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How Hindus protected &amp;amp; nurtured Sikhi🧵&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rajput-support&#34;&gt;Rajput support&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;jai-singh&#34;&gt;Jai Singh&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gurudwara Bangla Sahib was originally Bangla (palace) of great Hindu King Raja Jai Singh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Aurangzeb summoned 6 year old Sikh Guru Har Krishan, Jai Singh protected the Guru &amp;amp; offered him residence here. He donated Bangla to Sikhs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Year: 1661.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Aurangzeb summoned Guru Har Krishan. He wanted to take away Guruship from the Guru bestow it onto Ram Rai. The Great Rajput king Raja Jai Singh immediately realized that Guru&amp;rsquo;s life was in danger. He personally went to Kiratpur to pay respects to the child Guru.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sikh-jATification</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/articles/sikh-jATification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/dubious-bAbaisms/sikhism/articles/sikh-jATification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1615584051708178434.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest propaganda is that Sikhism gained popularity because of Hinduism&amp;rsquo;s archaic principles, particularly Varnashram. All Sikh Gurus came from one caste - Khatri and largely their children also married within their own community. If it was so egalitarian then why this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;caste-strictures&#34;&gt;Caste strictures&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SCs were barred from Golden Temple. The Mazhabis (SC) were forbidden to enter the Golden Temple for worship; their offering of karah prasad was not accepted and the Sikhs denied them access to public wells and other utilities. Khalsa Dharam Sastrar of 1914 laid down that the members of the untouchable groups (like the Mazhabi, Rahtia and Ramdasia Sikhs) did not have the right to go beyond the fourth step in the Golden Temple. The members of the fourfold varnas including Nai, Chippe, Jhivar, were instructed not to mix with persons belonging to the untouchable castes. Those who were guilty of breaking caste rules were classified as &amp;lsquo;patit&amp;rsquo; and shunned by the Sikh civil society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
