<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anti-pagan on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anti-pagan on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Charity sham</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/charity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/charity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Social and medical work was/ is used by the missionaries to prepare the ground for conversion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Though Christian propaganda may use the following creed to spread &amp;ldquo;1. Do good to your neighbours. 2. Forgive your enemies. 3. Spread my message all over.&amp;rdquo;, we have noted that Christianity is far more sinister.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mother-teresa-the-angel-from-hell&#34;&gt;Mother Teresa, the angel from hell&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christopher Hitchens &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/fighting_words/2003/10/mommie_dearest.html&#34;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;MT was not a friend of the poor. She was a friend of poverty. She said that suffering was a gift from God. &amp;hellip; Many more people are poor and sick because of the life of MT: Even more will be poor and sick if her example is followed. She was a fanatic, a fundamentalist, and a fraud, and a church that officially protects those who violate the innocent has given us another clear sign of where it truly stands on moral and ethical questions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Regarding the abysmal quality of care for her poor patients, we have plenty of testimony from disillusioned volunteers. [CH&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=65JxnUW7Wk4#t=382&#34;&gt;documentary shot&lt;/a&gt;.] Mother Teresa herself referred to the facilities as &amp;ldquo;Houses of the Dying&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736%2894%2991759-0/fulltext&#34;&gt;Lancet published&lt;/a&gt; a critical account of the care in Mother Teresa&amp;rsquo;s facilities in 1994. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nouvelles.umontreal.ca/udem-news/news/20130301-mother-teresa-anything-but-a-saint.html&#34;&gt;An academic Canadian study&lt;/a&gt; from a couple of years ago found fault with &amp;ldquo;her rather dubious way of caring for the sick etc..&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baptisms of the dying: In a speech at the Scripps Clinic in California in January 1992, she said: &amp;ldquo;Something very beautiful&amp;hellip; not one has died without receiving the special ticket for St. Peter, as we call it. We call baptism ticket for St. Peter. We ask the person, do you want a blessing by which your sins will be forgiven and you receive God? They have never refused. So 29,000 have died in that one house [in Kalighat] from the time we began in 1952.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As a general liar: &lt;a href=&#34;http://indiafacts.co.in/expose-mother-teresas-deceptions-demagoguery/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rome&#34;&gt;Rome&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Julian to Arsacius, High-priest of Galatia (362, on his way to Antioch in June?]&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The Hellenic religion does not yet prosper as I desire, and it is the fault of those who profess it; for the worship of the gods is on a splendid and magnificent scale, surpassing every prayer and every hope. May Adrasteia pardon my words, for indeed no one, a little while ago, would have ventured even to pray for a change of such a sort or so complete within so short a time. Why, then, do we think that this is enough, why do we not observe that it is their benevolence to strangers, their care for the graves of the dead and the pretended holiness of their lives that have done most to increase atheism? I believe that we ought really and truly to practise every one of these virtues. And it is not enough for you alone to practise them, but so must all the priests in Galatia, without exception. Either shame or persuade them into righteousness or else remove them from their priestly office, if they do not, together with their wives, children and servants, attend the worship of the gods but allow their servants or sons or wives to show impiety towards the gods and honour atheism more than piety. In the second place, admonish them that no priest may enter a theatre or drink in a tavern or control any craft or trade that is base and not respectable. Honour those who obey you, but those who disobey, expel from office. In every city establish frequent hostels in order that strangers may profit by our benevolence: I do not mean for our own people only, but for others also who are in need of money. I have but now made a plan by which you may be well provided for this; for I have given directions that 30,000 modii of corn shall be assigned every year for the whole of Galatia, and 60,000 pints of wine. I order that one-fifth of this be used for the poor who serve the priests, and the remainder be distributed by us to strangers and beggars. For it is disgraceful that, when no Jew ever has to beg, and the impious Galilaeans support not only their own poor but ours as well, all men see that our people lack aid from us. Teach those of the Hellenic faith to contribute to public service of this sort, and the Hellenic villages to offer their first fruits to the gods, and accustom those who love the Hellenic religion to these good works by teaching them that this was our practice of old. At any rate Homer makes Eumaeus say: &amp;ldquo;Stranger, it is not lawful for me, not even though a baser man than you should come, to dishonour a stranger. For from Zeus come all strangers and beggars. And a gift, though small, is precious.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digestion</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/digestion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/digestion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bede account : &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/609518656482095104&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Translation of Pope Gregory&amp;rsquo;s letter to the Abbot Melitus (This epistle is dated in the 19th year of the Emperor Maurice): &amp;ldquo;To his most beloved son the Abbot Melitus Gregory the servant of the servants of God We have been much concerned since the departure of our congregation is with you because we have not received any account of the good success of your journey When Almighty God shall bring you to the most man our brother Bishop Augustine tell him upon the most mature deliberation upon the affairs the English I have thought of that is that the &lt;strong&gt;temples of the idols in that nation ought not to be destroyed but let the idols that are in them be destroyed, let holy water be made and sprinkled in the said temples, let altars be erected and relics placed.&lt;/strong&gt; For if those temples are well built it is requisite that they be converted from the worship of devils to the service of the true God that the nation not seeing these temples destroyed may remove error from their hearts and knowing and adoring the true God may the more familiarly resort to the same places where they were wont. And &lt;strong&gt;because they were used to slaughter many oxen in the sacrifice to devils some solemnity must be exchanged for them&lt;/strong&gt; on this account - On the day of the dedication or the nativities of the holy martyrs whose relics are there deposited they may build themselves huts of the boughs of trees about those churches which have been turned to that use from temples and &lt;strong&gt;celebrate the solemnity with religious feasting. They are no more to offer up beasts to the devil but to slay and eat them to the praise of God&lt;/strong&gt; and return thanks to the Giver of all good for their satiety for thus while they are permitted these gratifications they will the more readily attend to what leads to inward and spiritual satisfaction For there is no doubt but that it is impossible to retrench all at once with obdurate minds because he who would ascend to the highest place rises by degrees or steps and not by leaps These things you are affectionately to communicate to our brother Augustine that he may consider how he is to order all things.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fightback</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/fightback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/fightback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;unsuccessful-fightback&#34;&gt;Unsuccessful fightback&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kalavai Venkat notes: &amp;ldquo;(Dalai Lama was refused a meeting by Pope Francis because it might annoy China [&lt;a href=&#34;http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/Pope-refuses-to-meet-Dalai-Lama-as-it-would-annoy-China/articleshow/45526567.cms&#34;&gt;TOI&lt;/a&gt;].) Prabhupada did the same. He went to the Vatican, and waited for an audition, only to be told that the pope had canceled the meeting. Sri Sri Ravishankar released audios where he had conversations with Jesus. Thich Nhat Hanh facilitated the shoplifting of the Buddhist meditation techniques and repackaging them as Christian meditation. When would these leaders realize an enemy for what he is?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iconoclasm</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/iconoclasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/iconoclasm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-pattern&#34;&gt;General pattern&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;saints-and-martyrs&#34;&gt;Saints and martyrs&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Many saints were criminals. &amp;ldquo;St&amp;rdquo; Boniface chopped down Thor&amp;rsquo;s Oak sacred to Germanics, &amp;ldquo;St&amp;rdquo; Nicholas said to have done same in Lycia to Hellenic sacred trees, &amp;ldquo;St&amp;rdquo; Martin did same (later Dutch Protestants defaced his cathedral)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you read martyr stories, you find saints going up and destroying shrines and icons, and then threatening to come back with a crusader army if the pagans refuse to convert. Then they get killed by pagans, which the Christians describe as the unjustified murder of an innocent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Christain saints and missionaries like Cyril and Bonerface were part communist &amp;ldquo;community organizer&amp;rdquo; and part Taliban death squad leader.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;There was a 1583 revolt in Goa (then under Portuguese) called Cuncolim revolt where the locals killed missionaries going around destroying temples, they were turned into &amp;ldquo;martyrs&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; beatified.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;digestion&#34;&gt;Digestion&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Digestion of icon-worship and polytheism within Catholicism and Eastern Orthodox Christianity&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In Catholicism there are many angels and saints, whose icons are worshiped, sometimes infused with prechristian rites, identities and traits.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;roman-empire&#34;&gt;Roman empire&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vandalism [&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/897631604574744580&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The charity route [Julian &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GhorAngirasa/status/894579184487481344&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;hasten to attack the temples with sticks and stones and bars of iron, and in some cases, disdaining these, with hands and feet. Then utter desolation follows, with the stripping of roofs, demolition of walls, the tearing down of statues and the overthrow of altars, and the priests must either keep quiet or die. After demolishing one, they scurry to another, and to a third, and trophy is piled on trophy, in contravention of the law. Such outrages occur even in the cities, but they are most common in the countryside. Many are the foes who perpetrate the separate attacks, but after their countelss crimes this scattered rabble congregates and they are in disgrace unless they have committed the foulest outrage. Temples, Sire, are the soul of the countryside: they mark the beginning of its settlement, and have been passed down through many generations to the men of today. - Libanius&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge destruciton</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/knowedge-destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/rivals/abe-disease/christianity/anti-pagan/knowedge-destruction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Deeds of the Abbots of St. Albans&amp;rdquo; by the pretAcharin Matthew Paris recounts a curious incident. In ~1000 CE in the ruins of the formerly Roman town of Verulamium (made St. Albans by the pretaka-s) Roman-age books in in a British language were found containing &amp;ldquo;invocations &amp;amp; rites of idolaters&amp;rdquo;. They were said to describe the worship of the &amp;ldquo;Phebum deum solis&amp;rdquo; (god of the sun Phebus)&amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;Mercurium, Woden Anglice appellatum&amp;rdquo;, Mercury, called Woden in English. The books were promptly &amp;ldquo;rejected&amp;amp; burnt by the abbots as &amp;ldquo;fabrications of the devil&amp;rdquo;. - MT&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
