<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</title>
    <link>https://hindutva.github.io/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on hindu-vichArAH हिन्दु-विचाराः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://hindutva.github.io/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hindutva revisit 2015</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/articles/sc_hindutva-revisit-2015-toi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/articles/sc_hindutva-revisit-2015-toi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Supreme Court revisits 21-year-old verdict on Hindutva ahead of crucial elections&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1995, the apex court had defined Hindutva as &amp;lsquo;a way of life&amp;rsquo;, which gave the BJP and the Shiv Sena considerable legal ground to justify their ultra-nationalist politics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;HIGHLIGHTS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Assembly elections in four states round the corner and controversies raging over cow vigilantism, triple talaq and uniform civil code, the Supreme Court is all set to revisit its two-decade old interpretation of the term Hindutva.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SC Hindutva - 2018 review</title>
      <link>https://hindutva.github.io/articles/sc-hindutva-review-2018_toi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hindutva.github.io/articles/sc-hindutva-review-2018_toi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dhananjay Mahapatra / TNN /  2018&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the recent past, political leaders have made visits to temples an inseparable part of their election campaign itinerary and strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Framers of the Constitution kept religion and politics separate. The Constitution mandates secularism as the cardinal principle of governance. But ground level politics has always tried to mix the two to form a potent vote catching chemistry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the chasm between communities widening, thanks to competing sectarian politics, there is a section of the intelligentsia which advises politicians to adopt a soft Hinduism line rather than advocate Hindutva, mistaking it for fanatic Hinduism, especially after the advent of cow vigilante groups. It is another matter that most states enacted laws banning cow slaughter in the 1960s when ‘cow and calf ’ was the election symbol of a political party.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
